<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-14T20:44:59-05:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/</id><title type="html">carissanicolewinn.github.io</title><subtitle>I'm a bisexual feminist who is passionate about discussing sex, religion, and politics.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Ways I Honor My Bisexuality (without kissing women)</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/ways-i-honor-my-bisexuality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ways I Honor My Bisexuality (without kissing women)" /><published>2019-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/ways-i-honor-my-bisexuality</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/ways-i-honor-my-bisexuality/">&lt;p&gt;Bi+ erasure and invisibility often make me feel like my bisexuality doesn’t actually exist unless I’m walking around holding hands with my obviously cis male partner and kissing an obviously cis woman at the same time while wearing a shirt that says “I’M BISEXUAL!” in all caps. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/ways-i-honor-my-bisexuality/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/honor-my-bisexuality.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feeling becomes especially heavy when I am publicly visible with my cishet male partner — my bisexuality sort of fades into the background until it is nonexistent. Thanks to cisheteronormativity, people tend to assume that I am straight because of the relationship I am in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, it is extremely important to me that I find ways to honor and express my bisexuality in daily life. While the idea of publicly kissing a woman while holding my partner’s hand does sometimes sound appealing, there are plenty of other ways I integrate my bisexuality into my life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intaking bi+ media and media created by bi+ folks (even if it isn’t explicitly queer in nature)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a broad category because there are so many forms of queer media! I spend a lot of time reading articles, listening to podcasts, and following topics on social media &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; bisexuality and other queer topics — learning more about our history and staying current on issues we are facing is important to me. However, I also try to prioritize the intake of media that is &lt;em&gt;created by&lt;/em&gt; bi+ folks no matter what the subject matter is. Supporting bi+ creators increases visibility for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listening to music with non-explicitly-male love interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This includes songs with gender neutral pronouns as well as songs about women, and I award bonus points if the artist is also not a cis man. Music receives it’s own category because it is a pervasive aspect of my life — almost every store, restaurant, or car ride features background music. Intentionally curating the music I hear is a small way that I can positively impact my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expressing to my partner when I find other people attractive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was forced to repress my attractions to everyone except cis men for so long that it is an act of resistance and bravery to express aloud when I find someone attractive. My partner is extremely encouraging in this endeavor and we find ourselves bonding over the occasional shared attraction. In this way, an expression of my bisexuality is actually facilitating intimacy-building between me and partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wearing or displaying bi pride colors and symbols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My partner gave me a lovely necklace that displays the bi flag colors, and another dear friend gave me a crescent moon necklace. While the bi colors are fairly self-explanatory, the moon is my personal symbol of bisexuality (see the screenshot below). I also display a bi pride flag in my bedroom, have many pride pins on my backpack, wear a bi pride colored ring stack, and own a multitude of pride-related pieces of clothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/motherfucking-moon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot of a tweet that says &amp;quot;We acknowledge that the whole moon exists even when, from Earth, we can only see part of it. So it really shouldn't be that hard to respect the wholeness of bisexual/pansexual/sexually fluid people even when they're in a monogamous relationship. It's fine to have phases, and outside appearances don't define you. We're the motherfucking moon.&amp;quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This tweet is from a friend who would rather not be named.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mentioning my bisexuality in social media bios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is important to me because it gives people a filter through which they will see all of my posts. By mentioning that I’m bisexual in a place that is fairly visible, I can help ensure that people don’t see pictures of me and my partner and assume I’m straight. When I put it in front of them, they will read what I post on social media through a different lens (which is great, because I interact with the world differently because I’m bi).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recognizing when I have a “celebrity crush” on a non-cis-male individual&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone has a celebrity crush, even those in monogamous relationships. It’s culturally acceptable to have crushes on celebrities, so acknowledging when I have one — no matter their gender — is really important to me in normalizing bisexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joining online communities for LGBTQ+ or bi+ folks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I wish I could surround myself with LGBTQ+ folks in real life who share my experiences, that isn’t always possible, so I intentionally seek out online communities of people who can relate to my daily reality. I’m part of several Facebook groups for varying demographics of LGBTQ+ folks and very active on Twitter. Some of my deepest friendships were formed in those spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating intentional space to honor my bisexuality not only positively impacts my well-being, it fosters intimacy with my partner and allows me to connect with others in deeper, more authentic ways. Even though our identities are not always immediately obvious to outside observers, we are healthier and more embodied when we lean into them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="lgbtq+" /><summary type="html">Bi+ erasure and invisibility often make me feel like my bisexuality doesn’t actually exist unless I’m walking around holding hands with my obviously cis male partner and kissing an obviously cis woman at the same time while wearing a shirt that says “I’M BISEXUAL!” in all caps.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/honor-my-bisexuality.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Queering Eve</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/queering-eve/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Queering Eve" /><published>2019-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/queering-eve</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/queering-eve/">&lt;p&gt;In every sermon and Sunday School lesson about Genesis 3, Eve was always the antagonist of the story. She was the one who disobeyed God, who communicated with the serpent, and who convinced Adam to eat the forbidden fruit. She’s the reason shame befell the human race and the reason God kicked them both out of the garden. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; But what if Eve wasn’t the bad guy, so to speak? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; What happens if we come back to this text with fresh eyes and a different hermeneutic? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/queering-eve/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/queering-eve.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s exactly what &lt;a href=&quot;http://samanthapfield.com/about-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Samantha Field&lt;/a&gt; asked us to do in her breakout session during the Q Christian Fellowship conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;queering-hermeneutics&quot;&gt;Queering Hermeneutics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samantha presented the idea of queering hermeneutics with three main principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Both/And — there are rarely binaries, even when the text seems to present two contradicting concepts. For example, God is &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; alpha &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; omega. Where can we interrupt the idea of binaries in the text?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Instability and disruption — how can we view the text through a lens of disrupting systems of oppression? How can this text be used to subvert, for example, cisheteronormativity or the kyriarchy?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Playing the trickster — sometimes the initial, “obvious” interpretation of the text should be turned upside down. What happens if we call good, evil and evil, good? What can be seen in the text when we flip the script?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She gave a few examples, but quickly turned us loose in groups to practice using these principles on a given passage. My group&lt;a href=&quot;#groupfootnote&quot;&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; ended up with Genesis 3, although our interpretation encompasses most of Genesis 2 as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost everything I’m about to write contradicts what I was taught growing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;returning-to-the-text--our-interpretation&quot;&gt;Returning to the Text — Our Interpretation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the creation of the world, God also created hierarchy. This is inherent to any system in which an all-powerful Being creates autonomous life — those created are automatically subservient to their creator because they do not possess equal knowledge or skills. Thus, Adam and Eve were thrust into a system of power imbalance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God also created the Tree of Life and the Tree of the Knowledge of Good and Evil. The existence of the Tree of Life tells us one of two things: either Adam and Eve were &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; created immortal and needed to eat the fruit of the tree to become immortal, or they &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; created immortal but had to continually eat the fruit in order to stay that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam and Eve were given one rule — do not eat from the Tree of the Knowledge of Good and Evil. Well, Adam was given the rule before Eve was actually created, and it is assumed that he passed it on to Eve. (Unless being created from Adam’s rib automatically gave Eve all the knowledge he possessed as well, but that’s a bit of a stretch.) The consequence of breaking this rule was dire. To quote the NRSV, “for in the day that you eat of it you shall die.” God told them that eating the fruit of this tree would kill them “in the day” that they ate it. God was not threatening the decay and eventual death of their bodies, but a sudden and immediate death as soon as they broke the rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t know for sure what kind of knowledge Adam and Eve had before eating the fruit, but it was obviously limited. Otherwise, the fruit from the Tree of the Knowledge of Good and Evil would have been irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This put the humans in quite a predicament. God was asking them to choose between a life of mediocre, limited knowledge or death. To choose between life under a hierarchy of power differential or death. Their ability to learn and grow was being restricted under penalty of death by a creator who had never, up to this point in the narrative, claimed to love them. God called them “very good,” but this only indicates that God was pleased with the handiwork of what had been created, not that God felt any particular way towards them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the serpent. For unknown reasons, he questioned Eve about what God had told her regarding the fruit. Eve’s answer was a bit of an exaggeration, but since she wasn’t alive when God made the original statement, it’s possible that she was simply repeating what Adam had told her. There’s no evidence to suggest that she willfully lied about the commandment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The serpent, however, challenges God’s statement that eating the fruit would kill the humans. He claims that God doesn’t want them to eat of it because it would cause their eyes to be opened to the knowledge of good and evil — the same knowledge that God possesses. “You will be like God,” he hisses. “You will not die.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eve becomes the heroine of the story when she resolves to call God’s bluff. She decides that obtaining the knowledge of good and evil is worth the risk of death; that she doesn’t want to live under God’s thumb, unable to fully understand the world in which she resides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eve rebelled against the hierarchy God had created and led Adam to do the same. As they ate the fruit, Genesis affirms that the serpent had told them the truth — “the eyes of both were opened,” just as he said would happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When their eyes were opened, Adam and Eve more fully understood their own nakedness, so they covered themselves. They hid from God because their nakedness caused them to be afraid. This makes sense, of course. They had just violated the only command God had given them, but with their newfound knowledge, they understood that the vulnerability represented by their nakedness was no longer something they wished to share with the God who had attempted to restrict their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their clothing was not about shame. Adam and Eve were not ashamed of their nakedness, but fearful of a God who could easily overpower them. They finally fully understood the world, on a level that was “like God,” and they knew that their most private and intimate parts were not safe in God’s presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eve is forced to bear the brunt of the blame. God is angered that the humans have attained the same level of knowledge and curses their existence. As punishment for leading the rebellion against the hierarchy, God extends it even further, placing Eve under the rule of Adam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God also banished them from the garden. The knowledge Adam and Eve obtained from the Tree of the Knowledge of Good and Evil combined with the immortality from the Tree of Life would have practically turned them into gods. This was a clear threat to God’s power, so the humans were sent away to suffer the consequences of their curses and eventually die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Eve did manage to prove that God was a liar. No one died the day they ate the fruit, which is what God originally threatened. Eve also successfully challenged the power structure under which she was forced to live, despite being brutally punished for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eve is &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; victor &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; victim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She shows us that power structures are worth disrupting even if God is the one instituting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She turns on its head the idea that a woman lured man into sin and instead challenges us with the idea that a woman led man into all knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we queer our hermeneutic, Genesis 2-3 becomes a story about a powerful woman who decided that death was better than a life in subservience to an oppressive force. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;groupfootnote&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:12px;color:#707070;&quot;&gt;&amp;#42;&amp;#42; Big thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pneumajustice&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jazzawazz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jazzy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/maguyton&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Morgan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/noblespencer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Spencer&lt;/a&gt; for being part of the group discussion on this passage!&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="christianity" /><category term="lgbtq+" /><category term="feminism" /><summary type="html">In every sermon and Sunday School lesson about Genesis 3, Eve was always the antagonist of the story. She was the one who disobeyed God, who communicated with the serpent, and who convinced Adam to eat the forbidden fruit. She’s the reason shame befell the human race and the reason God kicked them both out of the garden. But what if Eve wasn’t the bad guy, so to speak? What happens if we come back to this text with fresh eyes and a different hermeneutic?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/queering-eve.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Kind of Sex I Thought I Wanted</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-kind-of-sex-i-thought-i-wanted/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Kind of Sex I Thought I Wanted" /><published>2019-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-kind-of-sex-i-thought-i-wanted</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-kind-of-sex-i-thought-i-wanted/">&lt;p&gt;Purity culture trauma left me with a pretty severe case of vaginismus — I could barely insert small tampons, I couldn’t handle a gynecological exam, and I definitely couldn’t have penetrative sex. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/the-kind-of-sex-i-thought-i-wanted/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/the-kind-of-sex-i-thought-i-wanted.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(For more of my purity culture experience, read &lt;a href=&quot;/purity-culture-is-a-complex-trauma&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first discovered that my trouble with tampons was symptomatic of a larger issue, my biggest goal was to &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; have penis-in-vagina sex with my partner. Sure, I wanted to be able to make it through a gyno exam, but that was the least of my worries. When I got married and was unable to have intercourse because of the intense pain, I felt like a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purity culture taught me that it was my wifely duty to have sex with my partner. It also taught me that the only kind of “real sex” was penis-in-vagina intercourse. Having that kind of sex would cause me to lose my virginity (and also lead to destruction if not saved explicitly for heterosexual marriage).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I couldn’t make it happen after both my partner and I saved our virginity for marriage, the shame and sense of failure were overwhelming. I thought that my partner would be dissatisfied and leave me because I wasn’t giving him sex. I thought that I was being a terrible wife because I couldn’t please my partner. I thought that my body was broken and betraying me because it couldn’t do the one sex act it was made to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also in the midst of dealing with extreme emotional trauma surrounding sex. My sex drive was virtually nonexistent, I had extreme anxiety during sexual encounters, and the shame spirals I experienced were crippling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this culminated in months of avoidance. I didn’t want to think about sex, didn’t want to talk about sex, and definitely didn’t want to &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; sex. I felt stuck in a cycle of avoiding all things sexual for months, feeling guilty about not performing my wifely duty for my husband, agreeing to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; sexual, and wishing I was doing anything else — on repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little over a year into our marriage, I finally started going to therapy. I began slowly peeling back the layers of trauma and pain. (It was during this process that I admitted out loud for the first time that “I might be into girls.”) Wounds began to heal, and I started experiencing a desire for sex again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despite all of the mental and emotional healing, my physical problem of vaginismus persisted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overcoming vaginismus became a priority. I was fixated on being able to have intercourse with my partner. So, just before our 2 year anniversary, I started going to a pelvic floor physical therapist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five months of therapy later, the big day arrived. We had PIV sex! My hard work had paid off. I was a ball of emotions — elated, anxious that it had been a fluke, feeling more connected to my partner than ever before, proud of myself, and crying tears of joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even in the midst of feeling so much excitement, the actual experience of intercourse was underwhelming. I was uncomfortable despite the lack of pain and abundance of lube in use. I didn’t &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; much of anything while it was happening, much less anything close to pleasure. I found myself looking forward to when it would be over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried again, of course. And again, and again. Each time I found myself crossing my fingers and hoping that — &lt;em&gt;this time&lt;/em&gt; — it would be different. I so desperately wanted to enjoy it. I had worked so hard to be able to do this! PIV sex was supposed to be great! My partner had been patient for so long while I worked up to this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But each sexual experience with intercourse was disappointing. I felt the shame and fear begin to creep back in. &lt;em&gt;Why can’t you just enjoy this like a normal woman? Why isn’t this pleasurable for your body? Maybe your vagina is still broken. What if you tell your partner that you haven’t been enjoying these sexual experiences? Will he be upset? What if he still ends up leaving you because you could be having intercourse but don’t want to?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found myself consenting once again to sex that I knew, deep down, I didn’t really want to be having. All of the progress I had made with my sexual and bodily autonomy, as well as the trust between my partner and I, was fading. I was moving in the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that cisheteronormative conditioning is a bitch to unlearn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all of the work I had done to rebuild a healthier view of my sexuality — learning that virginity is a construct with no meaning or use other than allowing men to control my sexuality, accepting and cultivating my queerness, beginning to explore my kinks, becoming comfortable with my naked body — I still believed that PIV sex was the best, if not the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt;, type of sex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having this realization was like getting punched in the gut. I spent several weeks unable to think about anything else related to sex. I felt like I had failed, once again, at something sexual — despite the amount of work I had done in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamieleefinch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jamie Lee Finch&lt;/a&gt; created safe space for me to process this during our phone calls, and I was finally able to admit my feelings out loud. She reminded me that it’s okay to not enjoy penetrative sex and that I don’t have an obligation to perform certain sexual acts with my partner (both things I already knew, but shame spirals are emotional quicksand). She also talked me off the ledge of feeling like a failure by pointing out that deep inner perspective changes take time — my body’s emotions won’t always be in sync with what I mentally know to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After shedding a few tears, I realized that I needed to give myself permission to explore what kind of sex I &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; want to be having. I had already spent months arguing with people that the definition of “sex” can include all sorts of things — mutual masturbation, oral, anal, kink, etc. But those things were all theoretical, because &lt;em&gt;to me&lt;/em&gt;, sex was still associated with PIV. A conversation with my body needed to happen (and it is still happening!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m past the initial emotional chaos, I don’t blame myself for holding on to the idea of a sexual hierarchy. After all, it’s the only thing I had ever been taught growing up. My worth as a woman and a wife was almost entirely dependent on the lack of penile presence in my vagina. No wonder I placed PIV sex on a pedestal — it was the only sexual act that could completely alter my inherent value; thus, it must be at the top of the sexual pyramid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few months I’ve been communicating with my body &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; my partner. They have both been patient and endlessly kind as I figure out how to move forward in a way that more accurately acknowledges my sexual preferences. I still feel as though I haven’t made much progress in determining what I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; enjoy, but I have been making great strides in accepting my desires without judgment. The shame spiral is no longer lurking, just waiting for me to realize that I’m failing. I have accepted that PIV sex might never be something I enjoy, and the relief that washed over me with that acceptance was freeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prioritizing my sexual pleasure has finally become more important than the specific sexual acts which provide that pleasure. For now, that means I mostly have sex with myself using an external vibrator while realizing that masturbation is not a “lower form” of sex. It is empowering, healthy, and exactly what my body has been asking me to do. The sexual hierarchy in my brain is slowly crumbling, and in it’s place I am building a sexual mansion in which every room is stunningly beautiful and worth exploring.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sex" /><summary type="html">Purity culture trauma left me with a pretty severe case of vaginismus — I could barely insert small tampons, I couldn’t handle a gynecological exam, and I definitely couldn’t have penetrative sex.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-kind-of-sex-i-thought-i-wanted.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Only She Can Save Me</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/only-she-can-save-me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Only She Can Save Me" /><published>2018-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/only-she-can-save-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/only-she-can-save-me/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/only-she-can-save-me/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/beach-poem.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of me laying on a beach in the shallow water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; I walk daily in a world where &lt;br /&gt;
this picture&lt;br /&gt;
this swimsuit&lt;br /&gt;
this body&lt;br /&gt;
will cast doubt on the truth of my experiences&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was raised in a world where&lt;br /&gt;
this sensuality&lt;br /&gt;
this confidence &lt;br /&gt;
this body &lt;br /&gt;
were regarded as sinful and impure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was taught to believe that&lt;br /&gt;
this sexuality&lt;br /&gt;
this passion&lt;br /&gt;
this body&lt;br /&gt;
would cause men to do terrible things to me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so I spent 23 years repressing&lt;br /&gt;
this beauty &lt;br /&gt;
this freedom&lt;br /&gt;
this body&lt;br /&gt;
to save the souls of men&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but what I’ve come to realize is &lt;br /&gt;
this body&lt;br /&gt;
my body&lt;br /&gt;
SHE&lt;br /&gt;
cannot save anyone but ME&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if only I make space for her to do so&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="feminism" /><category term="sex" /><summary type="html">I walk daily in a world where this picture this swimsuit this body will cast doubt on the truth of my experiences</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/beach-poem.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Purity Culture is a Complex Trauma</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/purity-culture-is-a-complex-trauma/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Purity Culture is a Complex Trauma" /><published>2018-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/purity-culture-is-a-complex-trauma</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/purity-culture-is-a-complex-trauma/">&lt;p&gt;This blog post is a copy of a Facebook post I made, which was based on a Twitter thread. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Find the unrolled Twitter thread &lt;a href=&quot;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1035160280978808833.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, the original Twitter thread &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Carissa12Nicole/status/1035160280978808833&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;amp; the Facebook post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/carissa.nicole/posts/10218018893692610?__xts__[0]=68.ARCfhuMPjUcpqz7pJeWM16JrnfXGYxUYkW5-7CtEbSjEXXTTd5uHiH2xVX7wXmfz7-z2Yb5V5Xg6Ero-6Fln94GbgfsUwYcaZsw04NAZG4yqGyuczneCMZi6gorWM_j45EmTixr4uEI4rHJOlCbYNoYkS8n8J8y1cB9vrFQRACP0fqzy35cz&amp;amp;__tn__=C-R&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/purity-culture-is-a-complex-trauma/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/purity-culture.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cw: sex, purity culture trauma&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(lightly edited for Facebook aka I took out the big bad swears &amp;amp; the tweet numbers)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a few nights ago, I tweeted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“you ever just sit in your bathroom sobbing late at night because purity culture messed up your life &amp;amp; everything feels worse when you’re tired?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone replied &amp;amp; asked how purity culture did that, so here is a definitely-not-comprehensive-barely-begins-to-cover-it thread of my experience with the trauma that is purity culture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: how did #purityculture mess up my life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: how long you got? a thread..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Exvangelical #ChurchToo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;purity culture is the pervasive set of beliefs, structures, &amp;amp; actions that place a heavy focus on the virginity &amp;amp; “physical/spiritual/emotional purity” of women/girls&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it is heavily influenced by patriarchal beliefs such as male headship, women being unable to serve in the same capacity as men in the church (&amp;amp; sometimes world at large), complementarian gender roles (women are made to run the home, men to provide by working), etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it is also heavily influenced by a cisheteronormative/anti-LGBTQ belief system wherein virginity is defined by the lack of PIV sex (the only kind of “real sex”), oral/anal/etc are often considered sinful even WITHIN a hetero marriage, &amp;amp; gender binaries determine sex drive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;church/youth group/Christian school lessons on sex:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;men/boys have out of control sex drives &amp;amp; lust that they can’t control&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;women/girls want love &amp;amp; give sex to get it&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;virginity is a gift for your future husband &amp;amp; losing it cannot be undone&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;losing your virginity is the equivalent to being chewed gum, backwash in a cup, a rose with no petals, tape that has lost it’s stickiness, etc. these illustrations are uniquely applied to women/girls bc it is their responsibility to save this gift for future husband&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;modesty is imperative bc boys/men cannot control their eyes or lust, so it is the job of girls/women to keep them from stumbling. our bodies are dangerous &amp;amp; capable of causing men to sin, thus WE are sinning if we don’t cover up for the sake of men&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;even THOUGHTS are sinful, so you must work overtime to prevent even the slightest hint of sexual thought from entering your brain&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;sex outside het marriage is dirty, an abomination&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;masturbating is a form of cheating on future spouse &amp;amp; also lust, so dirty/sinful also&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there is a heavy emphasis on how terrible you will feel if you violate any of the purity standards that have been set for you, &amp;amp; so normal &amp;amp; age-appropriate sexual exploration becomes a vicious cycle of shame &amp;amp; guilt (sometimes for something as benign as holding hands!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;purity culture also intentionally withholds sex education, because children who aren’t taught about sex will obviously not think about sex, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this leads to people like me who cannot identify basic body parts well into my college years&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when you spend the first 20-some years of your life trying desperately to repress any sex drive or attraction you might feel bc allowing yourself to feel it would be sinful, &amp;amp; spinning in shame &amp;amp; guilt for failing, it is TRAUMATIC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;purity culture is a complex trauma&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it is a trauma of incidents compiled over a lifetime, no one particular thing ever seeming bad enough to rise to the level of traumatic, but put together it causes many of the same symptoms as sexual assault/abuse/trauma bc it is a form of sexual trauma&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got married &amp;amp; discovered sexuality is not a switch I can flip on as I was taught. Even the thought of having sex WITH MY HUSBAND caused anxiety &amp;amp; panic attacks, &amp;amp; actually attempting sex sent me spiraling in shame &amp;amp; guilt despite knowing “it’s okay now bc I’m married”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have vaginismus as a result of my trauma. This is a pelvic floor condition in which my vaginal muscles involuntarily contract &amp;amp; do not allow anything to enter as well as causing severe pain upon trying. this is also common in sexual abuse/assault survivors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cried myself to sleep for months. not only could I not figure out how to want or enjoy the sex I waited so long to have, but my body was physically betraying me. I was a failure &amp;amp; couldn’t give my husband what he needed. I was taught this was my wifely duty &amp;amp; I was failing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the sense of failure only worsened my shame spiral &amp;amp; we eventually gave up trying. I then felt guilty for being relieved that I didn’t have to think about sex any more, bc thinking about it still made me feel dirty as I had been told to feel my whole life to this point&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually started therapy &amp;amp; have started the long process of sorting through my trauma surrounding sex, but it’s an ongoing process. I’m now also in PT to deal with the physical aspect of vaginismus, but it’s a slow, painful process w/ no guarantee of full recovery&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on top of this, I’m bisexual. I repressed this aspect of myself even deeper than my sexual thoughts about men. I grew up being taught that I would go to hell, that LGBTQ+ folks are abominations, sexual perverts, disgusting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;despite changing theology &amp;amp; being LGBTQ+ affirming by this point, I still couldn’t admit to myself or anyone that I was bi. it took months of intense inner work in therapy to even come out to myself. imagine growing up &amp;amp; being instilled with such disgust for WHO YOU ARE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was never given space or tools to develop a healthy sexuality. I’m basically in 2nd puberty, trying to relearn &amp;amp; reconstruct my sexuality from the ground up after doing so much work to dismantle the lies I was given as a framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have trouble touching my own or my husband’s genitals, bc they were portrayed as dirty, gross, &amp;amp; sinful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggled for months with the idea that I couldn’t have real sex without being able to have PIV, but sex is so much more than that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my sex drive, when it does make an appearance, is still often guilt &amp;amp; shame ridden. it is so deeply ingrained in my body that sexual thoughts are evil, even when they are about my husband, that shame &amp;amp; guilt often override any sexual desire I might have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if I’m not careful, I still fall into shame cycles about the fact that I’m “still a technical virgin” because a penis has never graced my vagina with it’s presence. when you’re told for so long that’s what defines sex, it’s hard to break out of that mindset&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I harmed myself &amp;amp; my husband by saying yes so many times at the beginning of our marriage when I really didn’t want to. I thought I was sinning if I refused him sex, &amp;amp; so I forced myself to try. he struggles to trust my yes now, &amp;amp; I struggle to not resent his asking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪when I am able to muster up a bit of sex drive &amp;amp; we’re able to get past all the other baggage surrounding sex, I am unable to communicate DURING sex. I often feel disembodied, unable to speak or make any noise at all, unable to tell him what I like or dislike bc I DON’T KNOW‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪how am I supposed to know how I like to be pleasured when I was never supposed to touch myself? when I still feel dirty touching myself? when, even though it’s now “okay,” my body feels like a minefield &amp;amp; touching or thinking the wrong thing will give me a panic attack?‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪to circle back a little, I was also pressured to marry young simply by virtue of the culture I was in. “it is better to marry than to burn with passion,” &amp;amp; I was expected to become a wife &amp;amp; mother anyway. I am forever grateful that Jared has grown alongside me &amp;amp; we fit well‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪I was told that romance &amp;amp; “true love” would turn into sexual desire, that I didn’t need to worry about sexual compatibility or attraction bc it would fall into place if I followed the rules &amp;amp; stayed pure. turns out, I’m not all that sexually attracted to my husband&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪I’m gonna end this for now, but I really could probably write an entire book about how purity culture harmed me &amp;amp; messed up my life (bc I don’t wanna hear how my sexuality isn’t a big deal &amp;amp; my marriage should be able to function well despite all this)‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪this experience isn’t uncommon. there are SO MANY people who have been harmed by purity culture, &amp;amp; if you want to tell your story too, feel free to quote tweet or reply! I’ll end by linking some resources if you want to better understand the trauma that is purity culture‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪- everything &lt;a href=&quot;http://samanthapfield.com/tag/purity-culture/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Samantha Field writes about purity culture&lt;/a&gt; is fantastic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪- highly recommend Northwest Institute On Intimacy &amp;amp; Dr. Tina Schermer Sellers book &amp;amp; blog, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinaschermersellers.com/2015/03/24/how-the-purity-movement-causes-symptoms-of-sexual-abuse/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here’s a good starting point‬&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪- over at Love, Joy, Feminism there are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.patheos.com/blogs/lovejoyfeminism/the-purity-culture/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SO MANY posts&lt;/a&gt; to help you understand purity culture &amp;amp; the harm it does&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪- there’s an &lt;a href=&quot;https://ikdgstories.tumblr.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;entire Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to publishing stories from those who came out of the purity culture associated with “I Kissed Dating Goodbye”‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪- speaking of IKDG, even the author has acknowledged the harm his ideas did &amp;amp; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://joshharris.com/documentary/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;creating a documentary&lt;/a&gt; about it‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so there’s the sparknotes version of how purity culture has messed up my life &amp;amp; some resources, but feel free to ask any clarifying questions&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="christianity" /><category term="lgbtq+" /><category term="feminism" /><category term="sex" /><summary type="html">This blog post is a copy of a Facebook post I made, which was based on a Twitter thread. Find the unrolled Twitter thread here, the original Twitter thread here, &amp;amp; the Facebook post here.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/purity-culture.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bekah Learns Boundaries</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/bekah-learns-boundaries/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bekah Learns Boundaries" /><published>2018-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/bekah-learns-boundaries</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/bekah-learns-boundaries/">&lt;p&gt;The concept of setting boundaries is still relatively new to me. I didn’t know until recently that it is acceptable &amp;amp; normal to put boundaries on relationships. I thought that expending emotional energy on every person who entered my life was just the way it had to be. So this past week, I exercised my new understanding of this topic to lay down some pretty intense boundaries with someone who definitely deserved all the snark that came along with it. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; I recently received a message from someone I knew in college; I’ll call her Bekah. We played sports together, but were never very close. I wasn’t very close to many people, actually, because it’s hard to get close to people at a conservative Baptist college when you are secretly deconstructing your entire belief system. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Anyway, I haven’t spoken to Bekah in almost 3 years, but she just couldn’t help herself. She sent me a message about the fact that I came out as bisexual, &amp;amp; I felt compelled to respond. Jared helped me write the message (&amp;amp; he also made me take out all the &lt;em&gt;big bad swears&lt;/em&gt; *pouty face*). Below is the text of our messages. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/bekah-learns-boundaries/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/bekah-learns-boundaries.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dear Carissa,
I read the status you posted about a week ago. First, I would like to apologize for not writing this sooner. There have been many hours spent in thought over how to go about this message, so I pray that my speech and motivation is understood. Carissa, something that has honestly really been bothering me about what you posted is that you call yourself more of a Christian for being bisexual. Here is my problem with that, no where does it say that in God’s word. In fact, it says the opposite of that, which is why I am writing to you now. I am truly and deeply concerned about you and the path you are on. My concern stems from the fact that God calls what you are doing sin. I was looking through the Bible for verses on this exact topic and came to find it called nothing but sin. Please understand, I can only claim it as sin because that is what God’s word says. In Romans 1:21-32, it says, “For although they knew God, they did not honor him as God or give thanks to him, but they became futile in their thinking, and their foolish hearts were darkened. 22 Claiming to be wise, they became fools, 23 and exchanged the glory of the immortal God for images resembling mortal man and birds and animals and creeping things.
24 Therefore God gave them up in the lusts of their hearts to impurity, to the dishonoring of their bodies among themselves, 25 because they exchanged the truth about God for a lie and worshiped and served the creature rather than the Creator, who is blessed forever! Amen.
26 For this reason God gave them up to dishonorable passions. For their women exchanged natural relations for those that are contrary to nature; 27 and the men likewise gave up natural relations with women and were consumed with passion for one another, men committing shameless acts with men and receiving in themselves the due penalty for their error.
28 And since they did not see fit to acknowledge God, God gave them up to a debased mind to do what ought not to be done. 29 They were filled with all manner of unrighteousness, evil, covetousness, malice. They are full of envy, murder, strife, deceit, maliciousness. They are gossips, 30 slanderers, haters of God, insolent, haughty, boastful, inventors of evil, disobedient to parents, 31 foolish, faithless, heartless, ruthless. 32 Though they know God’s righteous decree that those who practice such things deserve to die, they not only do them but give approval to those who practice them.” This passage clearly shows that God sees homosexuality and bisexuality as a dishonorable passion, something that should not be done, and deserving of death. So you see, if I were to celebrate what you are doing then I would be giving approval to something that I know God says is wrong. By doing so, I would not be acting lovingly toward you, but hating you. It is not an act of love to watch and even encourage someone to continue living in sin, allowing them to get deeper and more attached to it. That is why I apologized at the beginning of this letter. I have allowed a week to go by without confronting you and trying to help you with this temptation. Do not think I have written this letter to make fun of or scorn you. I wrote this because I care about you and am extremely worried that you are headed down a path that leads to judgment. I do not want that for you! A few years ago, you encouraged me in my time of need. I am sorry I have not been there for you in the same way. There are more verses I found on this topic and would be happy to send your way if you would so desire. Carissa, I am praying for you and I hope to speak to you soon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dear Bekah,
I wanted to write back to let you know that your motivation was understood perfectly. Let me explain. We haven’t been friends for a while now. In fact, we haven’t even been social media friends, not even “facebook friends” for what little that even means. You are not &amp;amp; have not been involved in my life for several years. And based on that fact, what would make you think that you have the right, the relationship, or the position to write a message like this to me? Isn’t “building a relationship” supposed to be the first step in speaking into someone’s life? Why in the world would you think that you have any authority or reason to say any of this? You know absolutely nothing about me. And honestly, you don’t really want to. You didn’t care about my life before I came out and you don’t care now, you only feel a personal responsibility to tell me these things because of your own conviction. That’s why your motivation is selfish. You didn’t write this message actually thinking that it would have any effect on me. You wrote it for YOU. You were so bothered by my coming out post that you needed to clear your own conscience and be able to say “I did what I could” as if it was your responsibility, in the process ladening me with the same generic cookie-cutter thought process that I’ve been around my entire life. Don’t insult me by pretending I haven’t heard it all before. I understand that in your mind the logic is so airtight that you think “if Carissa believes otherwise, it must be because she forgot”. But that isn’t how this works. I did not forget, the logic is not airtight, and wasting your time writing out all the talking points you should be well aware I learned at the same school as you is just a product of the very dangerous presumption that your theology is undeniably correct to the letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, a small helpful hint for the next time you feel like writing a “convicting” message to someone you haven’t seen or spoken to in YEARS &amp;amp; who you weren’t even that close to in the first place:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your motives are not subtle and I promise people can and will continue to see right through them. Approaching topics like this from a holier-than-thou, “I possess knowledge that you don’t” standpoint is only going to alienate others, not convince them. If you believe your purpose as a Christian is to evangelize non-believers (which I am not, for the record), this is the opposite of how to achieve it. No reasonable person would actually believe that a message like this would have any impact on me or my life decisions. Why did you think it would mean something to me? You didn’t. It was for you to be able to say you did it. Why do you think I even care what you think or how YOU interpret the Bible? You can’t claim a monopoly on “Biblical truth” and tote it as the clear and obvious interpretation when the Evangelical church can’t even agree within itself on what is “clear”, let alone the whole of Christianity across the world. Don’t talk to me about “what God says” and expect that to have weight when Christians can’t even agree what God says. Ironically I probably know what you believe about this better than you do, because I put in the work studying it &amp;amp; deciding that it was wrong. I would be willing to bet money that you’ve never given serious, genuine study to the topic of LGBTQ+ “issues”. You just believed what you were taught. I have read hundreds of books &amp;amp; articles, watched lectures, done word studies. Meanwhile you cherry pick a handful of verses, the meaning of which someone else told you and you never gave it a second thought. Your certainty comes from a lifetime of conditioning and insulation from outside thought, not the strength of your belief itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope writing this made you feel better, because you wrote it out of a selfish &amp;amp; condescending desire to fix me. I imagine you also wrote it out of disgust, because I know that you once said you would quit cross country if you found out there was a gay person on the team. Well surprise, I was there the whole time. Luckily I didn’t have to tolerate your homophobia as badly as the other LGBTQ+ people surrounding you. Your interpretation of Scripture leads to the suicides &amp;amp; deaths of hundreds of LGBTQ+ people every year. There are many studies showing this. No good tree bears bad fruit. Your theology bears bad fruit. Period. I don’t have any fanciful ideas that I can change your mind on this, because if you’re the kind of abrasively dogmatic person who writes a message like this to someone you barely know, I can only imagine the kind of damage you would do to an LGBTQ+ person who has the misfortune of knowing you in real life. I want it to be very clear that I know you haven’t studied this, &amp;amp; I want it to be very clear that I actually have. I don’t need you to send me more Bible verses on the topic. I know &amp;amp; could quote to you all 7 “clobber passages”, &amp;amp; I could exegete each one &amp;amp; tell you why I don’t believe they say the things you are claiming. Your conservative white American English Bible is not “clear” on much of anything, &amp;amp; I’m tired of people like you trying to weaponize it against me. I don’t want your prayers. I’m not experiencing temptation. &amp;amp; I most certainly don’t want your homophobic “help” with this. Abandon your pretentious “love” &amp;amp; condescending “apologies”; they will only do people harm.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="christianity" /><category term="lgbtq+" /><summary type="html">The concept of setting boundaries is still relatively new to me. I didn’t know until recently that it is acceptable &amp;amp; normal to put boundaries on relationships. I thought that expending emotional energy on every person who entered my life was just the way it had to be. So this past week, I exercised my new understanding of this topic to lay down some pretty intense boundaries with someone who definitely deserved all the snark that came along with it. I recently received a message from someone I knew in college; I’ll call her Bekah. We played sports together, but were never very close. I wasn’t very close to many people, actually, because it’s hard to get close to people at a conservative Baptist college when you are secretly deconstructing your entire belief system. Anyway, I haven’t spoken to Bekah in almost 3 years, but she just couldn’t help herself. She sent me a message about the fact that I came out as bisexual, &amp;amp; I felt compelled to respond. Jared helped me write the message (&amp;amp; he also made me take out all the big bad swears *pouty face*). Below is the text of our messages.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/bekah-learns-boundaries.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Coming Out</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/coming-out/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coming Out" /><published>2018-08-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/coming-out</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/coming-out/">&lt;p&gt;“I never became more queer. I can’t become less queer. But my awareness of myself – my falling-in-love, non-discriminatory silly starry-eyed self that falls in love with people whose funny, gentle, kind, fierce souls shine out through their eyes whether they’re men or women – that queerness is a thing that I have discovered over time. And that queerness, and my growing understanding and acceptance of it, is who I am. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Being queer doesn’t make my life any less a testament to the glory of God or the work of God’s spirit in my life or make me less wholly, entirely Jesus Christ’s. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; The more queer I am, the more Christian I am.” [1] &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/coming-out/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/coming-out/nosering.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;selfie of me wearing glasses &amp;amp; showing off my new nose ring&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am publicly acknowledging something about myself that I have known for a while - I’m bisexual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I call myself bisexual because I acknowledge that I have in myself the potential to be attracted –– romantically and/or sexually –– to people of more than one sex and/or gender, not necessarily at the same time, not necessarily in the same way, and not necessarily to the same degree.” [2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/coming-out/noseringmeme.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tweet that says &amp;quot;are bisexuals born with nose rings or is it in our agenda&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some ways, this announcement doesn’t change much. I’m still happily married to a man I love deeply, &amp;amp; I accepted that &lt;em&gt;other people&lt;/em&gt; could be LGBTQ+ Christians well before I accepted that I, too, was part of that group. I haven’t had to make any huge theological shifts, I just had to accept that this part of me has always existed &amp;amp; will always exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why bother coming out? Why bother telling the world that I’m bi? Several reasons, actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to be fully known. I don’t want to worry about accidentally outing myself. I want to be able to acknowledge the fact that I have had crushes on celebrities of all genders. I don’t want to hide myself because I’m afraid of the opinions and theology I was raised on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more than those personal things, I want to be visible. I want my life to be part of a conversation that is so very important &amp;amp; so very absent from many of the spaces I grew up in. LGBTQ+ folks exist even in those places where they are most condemned, but hiding from yourself &amp;amp; others always leads to pain &amp;amp; trauma. I also want to be visible because there are lots of misconceptions &amp;amp; stereotypes about bi+ people. A big part of tearing down those ideas is living visibly as a bi woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here are a few answers to frequently asked questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jared supports &amp;amp; loves me &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; of who I am, not in spite of it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;my marriage is doing great&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am no less capable of commitment in relationships because of my bisexuality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am no more sexual or “promiscuous” than anyone else because of my bisexuality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in answer to any questions about my sex life, who I have or haven’t kissed in my life, etc.- that’s very weird to ask, please stop &amp;amp; reevaluate why you care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/coming-out/gaystreet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of me holding a bi pride flag in front of a street sign that reads &amp;quot;Gay Street&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I want to thank those people who have become my closest friends &amp;amp; support system, even if you’re “just an internet friend.” You know who you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&quot;https://laurajeantruman.com/2018/06/11/the-lie-of-the-queer-christian-zero-sum-game/&quot;&gt;Laura Jean Truman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] quote by Robyn Ochs&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="christianity" /><category term="lgbtq+" /><summary type="html">“I never became more queer. I can’t become less queer. But my awareness of myself – my falling-in-love, non-discriminatory silly starry-eyed self that falls in love with people whose funny, gentle, kind, fierce souls shine out through their eyes whether they’re men or women – that queerness is a thing that I have discovered over time. And that queerness, and my growing understanding and acceptance of it, is who I am. Being queer doesn’t make my life any less a testament to the glory of God or the work of God’s spirit in my life or make me less wholly, entirely Jesus Christ’s. The more queer I am, the more Christian I am.” [1]</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/coming-out/gaystreet.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dreading Christmas</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/dreading-christmas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dreading Christmas" /><published>2017-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/dreading-christmas</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/dreading-christmas/">&lt;p&gt;I have always been a bit of a Scrooge at Christmastime, especially when it comes to Christmas music. I can tolerate it and even get into the spirit for the week leading up to Christmas, but other than that, I can’t stand listening to it. Of course, when I was young, I looked forward to opening gifts and spending time out of school. We always visited my grandparents, and there was often snow on the ground for sledding. I have generally happy memories associated with Christmas. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; And yet, I find myself increasingly dreading the holiday. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; I don’t think it has much to do with Christmas, honestly. What isn’t there to love about a consumerist holiday veiled as religious celebration? It probably has a lot more to do with traditions and a culture surrounding it that feel more and more foreign to me as I distance myself from my upbringing. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/dreading-christmas/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/dreading-christmas.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;minefields&quot;&gt;Minefields&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christmas is all about family getting together. Unfortunately, as I have become progressive in my faith and liberal in my politics over the last year and a half, those gatherings are no longer as enjoyable as they once were. I dread the moment one of my family members makes a racist comment or disparages Muslims. It isn’t a question of &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; they will, but &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; they will, and each instance is an internal battle. &lt;em&gt;Is this the right moment to speak up? Am I truly an ally if I let it slide?&lt;/em&gt; I haven’t fully worked out how to choose my battles wisely, and walking into a family gathering full of conservative Evangelical Trump supporters is a minefield. It feels like the onus is on me to keep the peace by staying silent, but while this year has emboldened racists, homophobes, and bigots all across the country, it has also emboldened &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; to speak the truth, even if my voice shakes. I admittedly &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; like to argue, but since I get it from my dad, it’s a recipe for disaster – conflict just waiting to happen. I also know that it doesn’t really matter &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; I say or &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; I say it, the conversation is not going to be productive, as no one involved is there with an open mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;swapping-40&quot;&gt;Swapping $40&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have come to despise obligatory gift-giving, and there is nothing quite as obligatory as swapping an arbitrary amount of money with a member of your family simply because you are related. It could be in the form of gift cards, cash, or an actual gift, but let’s be real – there was a set price limit, and all you accomplished was swapping that amount of money. Personally, I would rather keep my $40 and spend it on something I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want, rather than crossing my fingers that the other person will figure it out. My husband’s family attempts to mitigate that fear by simply telling each other exactly what to buy, but that negates the fun of giving a gift in the first place! If I wanted or needed that item so badly, I would have simply bought it with my own $40 instead of telling you to buy it, making you buy gift bags or wrapping paper, and then trying to act surprised when I open it on Christmas. Also, if you come from a family that &lt;em&gt;doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; set price limits, navigating obligatory gift-giving can become even trickier. &lt;em&gt;How much should I spend on their gift? What if they spend a lot more than I spend? Will I look bad? Does it matter?&lt;/em&gt; The real problem is the fact that you are obligated to give them a gift in the first place; if you weren’t required to do so, any gift given would be sincere and it wouldn’t matter how much either of you spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-war-on-christmas&quot;&gt;The War on Christmas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am weary of trying to determine if someone’s &lt;em&gt;“Merry Christmas!”&lt;/em&gt; is sincere or if it’s a subtle &lt;em&gt;“screw you!”&lt;/em&gt; A holiday greeting should not be a weapon of communication intended to let all around you know how “Christian” you are. I am tired of hearing people discuss “how to keep Christ in Christmas” or “the reason for the season”. Cursory research shows that not only was Jesus not born anywhere close to December 25, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.history.com/topics/christmas/history-of-christmas&quot; title=&quot;History of Christmas&quot;&gt;the day of celebration was arbitrarily chosen by Pope Julius I, likely to correspond with the pagan holiday Saturnalia&lt;/a&gt;. The real “reason for the season” is probably a winter solstice festival. On top of all that, the consumerism that runs rampant around Christmastime is given top priority, even in most conservative families such as mine. Sure, we read the Christmas story from Luke before we open gifts, but it isn’t something to be celebrated – it’s merely an inconvenient tradition that stands in the way of the presents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;snow-slush-and-cold&quot;&gt;Snow, Slush, and Cold&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reason is definitely the most trite of everything I’ve said, but it still stands – I hate the cold. Snow can be pretty, but it comes at the price of chills and wet feet. Slush is perhaps the worst, as it is cold, wet, and also disgusting. The pros do not outweigh the cons for me, and while I know these things aren’t relegated to &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; Christmastime, that’s the time people generally wish for snow. But I don’t need a white Christmas; unless, of course, we’re talking about white sand beaches in the Caribbean somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="christianity" /><category term="family" /><summary type="html">I have always been a bit of a Scrooge at Christmastime, especially when it comes to Christmas music. I can tolerate it and even get into the spirit for the week leading up to Christmas, but other than that, I can’t stand listening to it. Of course, when I was young, I looked forward to opening gifts and spending time out of school. We always visited my grandparents, and there was often snow on the ground for sledding. I have generally happy memories associated with Christmas. And yet, I find myself increasingly dreading the holiday. I don’t think it has much to do with Christmas, honestly. What isn’t there to love about a consumerist holiday veiled as religious celebration? It probably has a lot more to do with traditions and a culture surrounding it that feel more and more foreign to me as I distance myself from my upbringing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/dreading-christmas.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Moment Your Opinion No Longer Mattered</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-moment-your-opinion-no-longer-mattered/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Moment Your Opinion No Longer Mattered" /><published>2017-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-moment-your-opinion-no-longer-mattered</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-moment-your-opinion-no-longer-mattered/">&lt;p&gt;On September 22, 2016, almost exactly a year ago, any weight your opinions may have held in my life vanished. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/the-moment-your-opinion-no-longer-mattered/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/the-moment-your-opinion-no-longer-mattered.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was recently married and along with that, recently freed to share my rapidly changing opinions. I was no longer held back by the idea that you might not pay for my schooling or the wedding, so I started sharing “controversial” things on my Facebook page. Refugees have obviously been a hot topic the last few years, and for some reason most of the Christians I grew up around were (and still are) adamantly against taking them in - especially ones from majority Muslim countries. (I know, I know, Sharia law and terrorists and such mean we don’t need to love them. You don’t need to explain yourself to me. *eye roll*)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following tweet from Donald Trump, Jr., was making the rounds:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/trumpjrskittles.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot of Trump, Jr.'s skittles tweet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response, I shared the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/eattheskittles.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot of &amp;quot;eat the skittles&amp;quot; post&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post caused quite a bit of drama as well as some good, productive conversation. What sticks out to me the most when I think back to it, however, is not the fact that some of my family and friends are seemingly heartless when dealing with Muslims in particular. It’s the response that my father posted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father, who spent a lot of time and money sending me to a private Christian academy, taking me to church, making sure I went to youth group, and paying for me to attend a Baptist college. It’s obvious which values he wanted to instill in me, and I would say that by all possible measures, he succeeded. The problem we’ve now run into is that I seem to have bought into a more radical living out of those values than he ever intended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See for yourself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your suggestion with this piece sounds good in theory, and is biblically a good response. But in real life, I guarantee you would think twice and maybe never eat the skittles. Your overt denunciation for the preservation of our ability to even remain the country God has given to us is starting to wear on me. Simply because we want to preserve our God given rights in this country does not mean we have no compassion what so ever for those in need. Your idealistic thoughts are noble, but naive to the world as it is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you catch that? Let me make it more obvious, without all the stuff in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your suggestion with this piece sounds good in theory, and is biblically a good response. But in real life… Your idealistic thoughts are noble, but naive to the world as it is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what you’re telling me, dad, is that I have presented a biblically good response that you deem idealistic, naive, and therefore unrealistic to actually live out? Do you hear yourself? Everything you’ve ever presented to me as the truth is centered around the Bible, and now you’re telling me that I got it correct biblically but not “realistically?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My opinions have surely been drifting further and further from yours, but not because I’m leaving the things you taught me behind. I’ve been walking away from your brand of Christianity because I see such a disconnect between the things you told me were true and the things you seem to believe. I’ll cover more of them in future posts, but this particular instance represents the first time the full weight of this discrepancy hit me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You made it blatantly obvious in your comment that you are willing to disregard biblical truths for your own comfort and personal safety. You also apparently place more value on your American rights than you do on biblical truths that might warrant forsaking those rights (but that’s a topic that deserves its own post, as I have since discovered many other areas of your life that such a view affects).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, though, it wasn’t what you said as much as what it represented. Up to the point that this interaction occurred, I still believed that you were just misguided in a few areas, but that you still believed the things you had taught me. I no longer think that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see now that your religion actually has very little to do with following Jesus and much more to do with serving your selfish American ideals. I don’t know where along the line you lost Jesus, or if you never truly wanted to follow him in the first place, but you also lost me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You lost my respect that day, because you didn’t even attempt to use the Bible to back your beliefs. At least people who use the Bible to back up their lack of love can semi-convincingly state that they’re still following the Bible. At least then we can debate biblical interpretation and practical application. You didn’t even try. You just outright ignored the Bible, cast it to the side, instead choosing to follow your nationalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your opinions about my faith and how it should inform my politics no longer matter to me, because you have demonstrated that they are not informed by the love of Jesus but by your love of self and country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despite the disappointment I felt upon having this realization, I will continue to love radically, just like you taught me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="christianity" /><category term="family" /><summary type="html">On September 22, 2016, almost exactly a year ago, any weight your opinions may have held in my life vanished.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-moment-your-opinion-no-longer-mattered.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">On Being a Woman</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/on-being-a-woman/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Being a Woman" /><published>2017-09-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/on-being-a-woman</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/on-being-a-woman/">&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of reading, specifically blogs, news articles, editorials, etc. Most of what I read I get from my Facebook feed. I was scrolling a few days ago and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/gretchen-kelly/the-thing-all-women-do-you-dont-know-about_b_8630416.html?ncid=engmodushpmg00000003&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; caught my eye. I couldn’t get it to load on my phone at the moment, so I moved on and forgot about it (much like the instances discussed in the article itself, ironically). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Today, it popped up again, this time shared by a friend with her own personal stories of male harrassment and living in a patriarchal, sexist culture attached to it. I was inspired, probably impulsively, to write up a small collection of my own stories. There are plenty more that I could tell, but these are the few that stuck out to me. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/on-being-a-woman/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/on-being-a-woman.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;true-stories-from-my-own-life&quot;&gt;True stories from my own life:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was on a work trip, unloading boxes from the truck by the street, &amp;amp; Jared was inside the building &amp;amp; not around, &amp;amp; 2 men were walking by on the sidewalk. One of them very loudly says “HEY BEAUTIFUL,” but I ignore it. Don’t make eye contact. Keep unloading boxes. A few seconds later, when it’s clear I’m not going to interact with his catcalling, he says, very loudly again, “WHAT A BITCH!” &amp;amp; suddenly I’m afraid that he might walk over to me, &amp;amp; I’m all alone, praying that Jared comes back soon. Thankfully, he keeps walking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m fresh out of high school working at Bob Evans as a waitress the summer before college. The customer base is significantly made up of the elderly, but that doesn’t stop old men from grabbing my hands, telling me that I have a nice “figure,” &amp;amp; leaving me one or two quarters as a tip if I don’t smile, laugh, &amp;amp; flirt back. So I quickly learn that to make money at this job, I have to flirt with the men I serve. Like the table of 4 college aged guys that I had to serve once. Everything they asked for was a sexual innuendo, with their eyes following my chest or my butt as I would walk away to get it for them. I giggled &amp;amp; did my best to play it up, knowing that I’d get a nice tip if I did. &amp;amp; I was right, they left me almost a 75% tip on their meal. My manager (also a man) saw my big tip &amp;amp; promptly walked over to me, bent down, &amp;amp; brushed off my knees as if there was dirt on them. The implication being that I was on my knees giving them sexual favors for such a big tip. The whole kitchen laughed, except for one other waitress who made eye contact with me as I blushed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was still working at that restaurant 2 summers later, &amp;amp; I’m the closing shift. The manager on duty has to walk me to my car, because a man has been hanging around the building trying to talk to the servers as they leave. By the time I’m leaving, it’s dark out, &amp;amp; I have to park by the dumpster where there’s no lamp light because you always save the best parking spots for customers. But once, my manager doesn’t walk me out, &amp;amp; I clutch my keys between my fingers, goosebumps on my arms even though it’s summertime. Thankfully, the creep wasn’t around that night, but who knows what would have happened if he had been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was working at Sears one summer, &amp;amp; a coworker kept getting too close to me physically &amp;amp; trying to flirt with me. My manager informed me that “he’s just like that” so I shouldn’t “let it bother me.” He was uncomfortably close one too many times, &amp;amp; I actually asked him to stop (not told, asked. I wasn’t even mean). He then got angry with me, &amp;amp; since I was the new employee, he successfully convinced a large portion of my coworkers that I was a stuck up bitch. It took me weeks (over 3/4 of the summer) to find more than 1 person who would willingly eat lunch with me because of it, although I did successfully re-convince most of them that I was a nice person by the end of the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;minimizing-suppressing-ignoring-denying&quot;&gt;Minimizing, Suppressing, Ignoring, Denying&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/gretchen-kelly/the-thing-all-women-do-you-dont-know-about_b_8630416.html?ncid=engmodushpmg00000003&quot;&gt;The Thing All Women Do That You Don’t Know About&lt;/a&gt; does a great job of describing the small incidents that quickly add up in daily life. The glances at our chests, the demeaning nicknames, the way men will stand just slightly too close. Pieces of the bigger picture, one that is hard to recognize even as a woman who lives it. Looking back on most of my stories, I didn’t know that those instances were anything other than normal. I grew up in a culture that taught me to ignore “those” type of men, because their actions were expected. But now, I know that my body is not something to which men are entitled. I know that my time, my feelings, and my affection are not something I must give to anyone who demands it. I know that it is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; normal to constantly put my guard up when interacting with men, whether at work or just walking down the street. But I also know that it is difficult to recognize when you are so entrenched in the system, and almost impossible if you are outside of it. I must learn to stop minimizing, suppressing, ignoring, and/or denying these so-called “small” instances and instead, start exposing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave you with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/TheAmyCourts/posts/10155136279258353?pnref=story&quot;&gt;these words&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This line we women dance - of defending ourselves and our right to exist, protecting ourselves from men who feel entitled to our bodies and our conversation, while avoiding angering them and endangering ourselves further - is a daily thing. We can’t go to the store, go for a walk, or go to work without encountering this kind of behavior on the regular.
It is exhausting. 
It’s dehumanizing. 
It’s being a woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="feminism" /><category term="sex" /><summary type="html">I do a lot of reading, specifically blogs, news articles, editorials, etc. Most of what I read I get from my Facebook feed. I was scrolling a few days ago and this article caught my eye. I couldn’t get it to load on my phone at the moment, so I moved on and forgot about it (much like the instances discussed in the article itself, ironically). Today, it popped up again, this time shared by a friend with her own personal stories of male harrassment and living in a patriarchal, sexist culture attached to it. I was inspired, probably impulsively, to write up a small collection of my own stories. There are plenty more that I could tell, but these are the few that stuck out to me.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/on-being-a-woman.png" /></entry></feed>