<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-06-30T01:08:23-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/</id><title type="html">carissanicolewinn.github.io</title><subtitle>I'm a bisexual feminist who is passionate about discussing sex, religion, and politics.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Procreation Problem</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-procreation-problem/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Procreation Problem" /><published>2019-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-procreation-problem</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-procreation-problem/">&lt;p&gt;A common objection to the validity and holiness of LGBTQ+ folks living and being in relationship with one another is that the Creation story makes it obvious that “those kinds” of relationships or lifestyles are unnatural. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/the-procreation-problem/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/the-procreation-problem.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The argument usually goes something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“LGBT people can’t procreate! God didn’t create them to fit together, so it’s obvious that their lifestyle is sinful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;let-me-tell-you-a-story&quot;&gt;Let Me Tell You A Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Disclaimer: this is the story as I was taught it growing up. It is an extremely literalist reading of Genesis, and while not necessarily the norm in Christianity as a whole, it is definitely the norm in white Evangelical and adjacent circles. This reading is the basis for many theological convictions prevalent in conservative American Christianity.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, God created Adam and Eve. They were the only two humans on the entire planet, so God joined them in holy heterosexual matrimony and commanded them to be fruitful and populate the earth with more humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then they discovered that one off-limits tree and ate it’s fruit. Suddenly they’re naked and God’s cursing them and kicking them out of their garden, but he still wants them to create more humans — it’ll just be a lot more painful now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Adam and Eve get to it. They had an entire planet to populate, so we can probably safely assume that as soon as Eve recovered from having one baby, they were sexing it up to try for the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- This pattern continued for at least the next 10 years, but probably for much longer. Humans were said to have lived a lot longer back in these early days, but it's most likely safe to assume that puberty started around the same age as it does for humans now. So about 13 years into this process, Adam and Eve's children are ready to take on the task of populating the earth. --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the recovery period and duration of time between children obviously varied, Adam and Eve would have continued this pattern for quite some time. As soon as a few of their children hit puberty, it was their turn to take on the task of populating the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was just one little problem. The only other people available for procreation activities were their parents and their siblings. The Genesis account doesn’t go into detail here, but it’s extremely obvious that some incest took place in order to complete this fruitful mission. Even several generations out, people would have been marrying and procreating with their cousins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This&lt;/strong&gt; is the story on which a lot of Christians base their theologies of sexuality and gender. Of course there are other passages, but Christians like to come back to this story as foundational, especially in discussions about LGBTQ+ folks and our relationships. Often, a few key points dominate the discussion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adam and Eve are clearly created as a man and a woman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;they are married (in the sense that God joined them together for life)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;they can procreate (and so are obviously made to fit together sexually, unlike LGBTQ+ folks and their partners who cannot “naturally” procreate)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;they are obviously heterosexual (generally based on the fact that they got married to each other)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;this story provides a template for sexual relationships today — namely, that marriage is when one heterosexual man and one heterosexual woman join together in relationship for life and are able to procreate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot to unpack here, so let’s dig right in.
​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-missing-from-the-creation-story&quot;&gt;What’s Missing from the Creation Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing we need to acknowledge is that there are certain concepts and ideas that we read back into the text, concepts that are “missing” from the story but we assume are present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science and language have evolved to give us not only a better understanding of certain things, but also better words to describe them. The author of the Creation narrative didn’t have any words other than “male” and “female” to describe Adam and Eve. When the text was written, those terms had all sorts of cultural implications (as they still do today!). Male and female were not only a reference to sex (“this person has a penis and testicles” or “this person has a vagina”) but also a reference to gender norms (male/man and female/woman were practically interchangeable). However, we now know that these sex and gender binaries are scientifically inaccurate (as well as not being interchangeable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Largely, those who argue against these scientific realities attempt to do so by pointing to this text as proof. Such justifications rely on faulty hermeneutics, proof texting, and a decent amount of cognitive dissonance to make their point. I majored in theology at a conservative Baptist college, and one of the first rules of interpretation we were given was to always consider the historical context, the knowledge possessed by the author, and the point the author was making to their original audience. In order to claim that the Bible contains proof that only two biological sexes/genders exist, one must ignore all three of those categories as well as scientific advancements since the text was written. The principles &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; taught me in their school are being ignored for the sake of justifying conservative talking points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What all of this means is that the concept that the Creation story presents us with factual evidence of a male/female binary (whether talking about sex/genitals/chromosomes &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; gender) is ridiculous. The story was never meant to give us information about those topics, and assuming that the author intended those sorts of takeaways is a huge interpretational leap that we simply cannot make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of resources available if you want to do more reading on the topic of biological sex and gender. The discussion would take up more blog posts than I have knowledge or room to write, especially within the larger scope of discussing the Creation story. If you’re new to the idea that even “biological sex” isn’t a binary, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1035246030500061184.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt;, then head on over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://not-binary.org/statement/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this letter&lt;/a&gt; written and signed by a bunch of scientists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;descriptive-vs-prescriptive&quot;&gt;Descriptive vs Prescriptive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another facet of interpretation that is often overlooked is whether a passage is &lt;em&gt;descriptive&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;prescriptive&lt;/em&gt;. A descriptive passage is one that simply tells us what happened. A prescriptive passage, however, is meant to teach us how to live our lives; it gives us something to emulate. We run into problems when we conflate these two story types or misinterpret passages as one type when they are most likely the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, the people who fall back on the Creation story in their theologies of sexuality and gender &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; consider Genesis to be narrative in type (other options found elsewhere in the Bible might include poetry, epistle, wisdom literature, etc). By definition, narrative literature is descriptive. It is telling a story of something that &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; happen, not something that &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; happen. The most conservative, literal readings of the Creation story must see it as a narrative in order for it to be historical. Otherwise, their theologies surrounding the creation of the world would come crashing down from lack of foundation. But these folks don’t get to have it both ways. If the Creation narrative is descriptive, then there is no precedent for claiming that what is described is also the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; way things should function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see evidence of this in other aspects of the Creation story. God created day and night, but sunsets break that binary. God created land and sea, but beaches break that binary. God created birds of the air and fish of the sea, but flying fish and swimming birds break that binary. While it is true that God created day and night, land and sea, and birds and fish, God didn’t &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; create those things. There is only description, not prescription. In the same way, while God created male and female, there is room for other options in between or even outside that binary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- (&quot;a major aspect of this story that they would certainly condemn emulating&quot;)--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another problem with seeing the Creation story as prescriptive is that there is a major aspect of this story that people almost always condemn emulating — that little bit about incest. If we were taking this story at face value — as if every single person is either male or female, as if every person should marry someone of the opposite sex, as if those couples should all have children — we can’t ignore the fact that there are siblings marrying each other and procreating in the story. Reading this narrative as prescriptive means, at the very least, that we should allow and possibly encourage siblings to do this. The irony here is that scientific advancements — the same scientific advancements that are ignored when it comes to gender and sex — are one of the main reasons we have made it illegal (or at least highly discouraged) for siblings to procreate, as well as the fact that cultural norms — the same kinds of norms that are ignored when interpreting the Creation story — discourage that type of love and attraction between siblings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lgbtq-folks-cant-procreate&quot;&gt;LGBTQ+ Folks Can’t Procreate?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve gotten a few of the interpretational issues out of the way, let’s talk about the underlying assumption in this argument that LGBTQ+ folks can’t procreate (at least without the help of “unnatural” means like sperm donors and IVF).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a cis bisexual woman. Does my ability to procreate suddenly disappear because I identify as LGBTQ+? Of course not. Since I am partnered with a cis man, I could easily attempt to have children “the natural way” if I chose to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all we know, Adam and Eve could have both been bi, pan, queer, demi, ace, etc. We have no evidence that they were heterosexual (or even cisgender!). Combine this with the knowledge that, statistically, the highest percentage of people are identifying as LGBTQ+ in US history, and the chances of &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; Adam and Eve being &lt;a href=&quot;#definitionfootnote&quot;&gt;allocishet**&lt;/a&gt; fall dramatically. The percentage of folks identifying as LGBTQ+ has been steadily rising in our country as the social climate becomes more accepting (despite some recent political setbacks in that arena), presumably because knowledge of the spectrum of identities and the relative safety to come out is at an all-time high. Given a “perfect setting” in which they had absolute safety and knowledge required to label their sexuality and gender, I think it’s highly likely that one or both of the first humans would have identified as LGBTQ+.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The assumption that Adam and Eve were both allocishet relies solely on the fact that they were partnered with each other and able to procreate. Cultural norms that see an allocishet identity as “normal” influence this assumption more than the actual Creation narrative, which — given what we know about narratives, science, and Biblical interpretation — is unable to provide us with this information. When Christians read the Creation story and see Adam and Eve as allocishet, it’s because they have been culturally conditioned to see &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; as allocishet until they announce otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This argument is also highly reductionist. The umbrella term of LGBTQ+ contains a wide range of identities, and within those identities there are many pairings of people who can still procreate. For example, two gay men could potentially “naturally” procreate if one of them was a trans man. Reducing the entire LGBTQ+ community to the instances in which a couple cannot procreate is disingenuous at best and explicitly harmful at worst. These ideas contribute to erasure and further stereotypes about LGBTQ+ folks while at the same time providing fodder for the people actively campaigning to take away our right to exist freely in this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-purpose-of-marriage-and-sex&quot;&gt;The Purpose of Marriage and Sex&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem with this argument is the way it treats the concepts of marriage and sex. The underlying assumption in claiming that LGBTQ+ relationships are “obviously sinful” because the couple may not be able to procreate is that the &lt;em&gt;purpose&lt;/em&gt; of marriage, and ultimately sex, is to make babies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea can be attributed to both cultural norms and religious ideals. We live in a society that still pressures married women to have children. When childfree, married women start nearing age 30, they are often the subject of insensitive jokes about ticking biological clocks. In conservative religious contexts, this pressure is compounded by teachings which claim that women were explicitly created to bear and raise children as their duty to the Lord. One prominent example of these teachings is The Nashville Statement, which explicitly claims marriage is to be “procreative” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cbmw.org/nashville-statement/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Article I&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, however, conservative religious folks don’t hold &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; tightly to the idea that married women &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; have children. Faint whispers of feminism have touched even those circles, and it is commonly acceptable to be married and childfree (though the pressure and insensitive jokes remain). These marriages are seen as holy and good despite the fact that they are not procreative, even by choice. (The way that these beliefs impact people affected by infertility and other related issues would take up an entire post on its own.) Thus, while our society often pressures married women to have children, it also fairly readily accepts those who cannot or choose not to do so without questioning the validity of their relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Procreation can be &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; purpose of marriage or sex, but it is not &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; purpose of marriage or sex. Then what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the purpose of marriage or sex? Our society often answers this question with one word — love. However, only the people involved in the marriage or sex can truly answer this question. No one can dictate what marriage or sex means to someone else, and as long as everyone involved is a consenting adult, the only thing we can know for sure is that absolutes about the purpose of these concepts are unfounded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worth of a person or a couple is not dependent on the ability to have children. The validity of a relationship is not called into question because the sex is not resulting in babies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of marriage is not procreation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of sex is not babymaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This same belief should also extend to LGBTQ+ relationships. It makes no difference whether they are able to have children or choose to do so. These relationships are valid and worthy of the same respect we give to childfree heterosexual couples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we’re here, I also want to note that science is an incredible tool that gives people in many different situations the opportunity and ability to have children who may not have been able to do it “the natural way.” No one bats an eye when a heterosexual couple utilizes IVF, sperm or egg donors, or a surrogate in order to have children. But as soon as a gay or lesbian couple choose to go that route, they are told that their use of “unnatural” means is proof that their relationship is illegitimate. This double standard points out yet another problem with the original argument being made against LGBTQ+ relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-takes-a-village&quot;&gt;It Takes A Village&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our communities benefit from the presence of childfree adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; people in our lives who can take on different roles because they are childfree. Certain vital occupations require long hours and the ability to be on call at any time for emergencies. Working parents turn to those without children for help with their own kids. Some people choose to work with children in different settings instead of having their own. Plus, what would we do without the fun aunts and uncles of the world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would also do well to remember that many couples who cannot or choose not to have biological children will foster or adopt. This is another area where double standards abound — allocishet couples who choose to foster or adopt are celebrated while LGBTQ+ couples are condemned. While these couples are not saviors, they can be vital to the welfare of a community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lives of the children already present in our communities are enriched because our communities are made up of a wide variety of people, including those in the LGBTQ+ community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-are-valid&quot;&gt;We Are Valid&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that there are other “Biblical arguments” to be made against LGBTQ+ relationships (although none are convincing, in my opinion). However, using the Creation story as a foundation does not hold up under almost any level of scrutiny. It requires assumptions to be made and hermeneutics and science to be ignored, which does not make for a strong argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no problem with the fact that some LGBTQ+ folks in relationship cannot procreate, just as there is no problem with the fact that some allocishet folks in relationship cannot procreate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LGBTQ+ folks and the relationships we enter into are holy and valid. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;definitionfootnote&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#42;&amp;#42; Allocishet is shorthand for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.womenshealthmag.com/sex-and-love/a21727877/allosexual-definition/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;allosexual&lt;/a&gt; (allo) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.womenshealthmag.com/relationships/a26087944/what-is-cisgender/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;cisgender&lt;/a&gt; (cis) heterosexual (het).&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="lgbtq+" /><category term="christianity" /><category term="sex" /><summary type="html">A common objection to the validity and holiness of LGBTQ+ folks living and being in relationship with one another is that the Creation story makes it obvious that “those kinds” of relationships or lifestyles are unnatural.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-procreation-problem.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Father’s Day</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/fathers-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Father's Day" /><published>2019-06-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/fathers-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/fathers-day/">&lt;p&gt;You raised me to crave your approval. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other than God’s approval, yours was the most important thing I could have. I know you just wanted the best for me; at least, the best that I could have as a woman. There was always a subtle conflict between the church message that women should be submissive wives and mothers and what you told me - that I could do anything. That I was intelligent and capable. That I was strong. There was always a subtle conflict between those messages you tried to instill in me and the reality of how you treated me — as weak for having emotions. As your property to give away to my future husband for having a vagina. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/fathers-day/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/fathers-day.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, I strove for perfection. It started early. You had me reading and speaking in full, articulate sentences before I was in kindergarten. You often bragged that I was just like “a little adult.” You treated my body as an adult, too. Covered me up, shamed me for my flesh. I was grown too early despite not actually hitting puberty until I was 16. All I ever wanted to do was please you. But while my friends were getting stickers or ice cream or dollars for Bs and Cs, I was getting scolded for A minuses. I never got a B on a report card in my life. I was too afraid to fail, to fail YOU. By the time I got to college, it was second nature. I got lucky that I love the sport I played, because being a bench warmer was simply not an option. I know that all you wanted was to see me succeed, but would it have killed you to bite your tongue a few times instead of constantly critiquing? Yes, it made me better at the game, but it also made me better at flinching every time you’d yell, embarrassed that you might get thrown out of the gym — again. Hearing you say that you are proud of me was what I’ve always wanted. You set my life up in such a way that your approval is practically approval from God himself. And you did tell me, sometimes. Usually only after really large accomplishments, but there were times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m truly an adult. Now that I’ve made some extremely difficult decisions about faith and politics and identity. Now that I am independent and doing well and living a happy life. Now you’ve ripped the approval that I sought after right out of my hands. You set me up to fail if I didn’t do exactly as you always wanted. You raised me to see myself as a failure if you weren’t behind me. Now I grieve on Father’s Day because I know that you aren’t proud of me. I grew up hearing you talk about people. I know what you think of me now. I can’t continue striving for approval that I’ll never earn, but I desperately want it. So today, instead of wishing you a happy father’s day, I’m crying myself to sleep. Because I will never be the daughter you envisioned, and I doubt you will ever be proud of me again. And I need to learn to be okay with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know you loved me and did what you thought was best. But right now, I’m not so sure you love me. I don’t know if you’ll ever be able to love me for who I truly am. I grappled with that today. I’m not okay with that yet. But I will be eventually, because I have to be. Because I AM intelligent, capable, and strong, just like you always wanted.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These words, written last year on Father’s Day and resurrected from the depths of my iPhone notes, still mostly ring true. I believe more than ever in my own intelligence, ability, and strength. However, I have endured far too many harsh words in the name of your love to still believe that you love me. To quote &lt;a href=&quot;/not-your-prodigal/&quot;&gt;another post of mine&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… but you don’t love me. You love the &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; of me. The idea of having a daughter who grew up to birth your grandbabies and be a stay at home mom and vote Republican. The idea of a meek, submissive wife who cooks for her husband and teaches Sunday school every few months at church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, I grieved on Father’s Day. I hadn’t even come out yet, but I knew what would happen when I did. Last year was the first Father’s Day in my life that I didn’t at least text you to wish you a happy day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year was the first time I listened to my body and didn’t force myself to send you an obligatory, half-hearted text. I finally allowed myself to begin grieving, to work on moving past my need for your approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to report that I’ve made great progress in that department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to report that I have the approval of my chosen family — folks who care more about me than you could ever understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to report that I finally have the approval of the person who means the most — &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m &lt;strong&gt;happy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So happy Father’s Day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="family" /><summary type="html">You raised me to crave your approval. Other than God’s approval, yours was the most important thing I could have. I know you just wanted the best for me; at least, the best that I could have as a woman. There was always a subtle conflict between the church message that women should be submissive wives and mothers and what you told me - that I could do anything. That I was intelligent and capable. That I was strong. There was always a subtle conflict between those messages you tried to instill in me and the reality of how you treated me — as weak for having emotions. As your property to give away to my future husband for having a vagina.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/fathers-day.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Not Your Prodigal</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/not-your-prodigal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Not Your Prodigal" /><published>2019-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/not-your-prodigal</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/not-your-prodigal/">&lt;p&gt;“The story of the prodigal son comes to my mind. It is the only way I will be able to deal with this. I’ll wait for you with open arms when you come back home… until then, I’ll pray for you to have your eyes opened by the only true God that you have put on the back burner…“&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These words, sent to me by my father, may seem innocuous. Maybe they even seem loving or kind. But make no mistake — these words, and the others that accompanied them, are manipulative, abusive, and deeply hurtful.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What prompted this message? I came out as bisexual. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/not-your-prodigal/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/not-your-prodigal.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this was death by a thousand cuts. Our relationship, if you could call it that, was deeply damaged well before this happened. My coming out simply angered him enough that he finally said what he had been thinking for a while — that I “made [him] sick to [his] stomach and about to throw up,” that he is “absolutely disgusted” with me, that I am “completely deceived by the devil,” that my decisions are a result of “mental illness,” and that there is “not a chance” of “even one scintilla of acceptance” (and yes, these are all direct quotes from other portions of the message above).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, I did deconstruct my entire belief system and turn into a queer, sex-positive, leftist feminist who regularly critiques my former belief system on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I still tried to show up at family gatherings despite the Fox News playing in the background. Despite the racist commentary on, well, everything. Despite the misogyny behind every remark on what I’m wearing. Despite the prodding “jokes” meant to provoke me to argue or fight back. It was tense; oh, it was so tense. But I still showed up, for over two years, despite a distinct lack of evidence that my family was ever going to meet me in the middle and at least turn off the conservative talk radio while I was around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I came out and received &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; message in response? I stopped showing up. I stopped responding. I stopped accepting my role as the familial black sheep relegated to shameful silence at the dinner table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I refuse to accept the position of prodigal child. &lt;strong&gt;I am not your prodigal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a wayward daughter making poor decisions that harm others or myself. I am not experiencing deep inner sadness or turmoil due to my life decisions. I am not secretly unhappy or trying to fill a void in my soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By calling me your prodigal child, you are telling me that you hope my life becomes so unbearably awful that I have no choice but to return to your way of life and belief. By asserting that you are praying for my eyes to be opened, you are praying for catastrophe in my life to break me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is neither healthy nor loving to wish harm on a person with the hope that they will convert to a specific religious belief under duress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You claim to pray for my destruction because you love me, but you don’t love me. You love the &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; of me. The idea of having a daughter who grew up to birth your grandbabies and be a stay at home mom and vote Republican. The idea of a meek, submissive wife who cooks for her husband and teaches Sunday school every few months at church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my refusal to meet your expectations does not make me your prodigal child. I am not sinning by discarding the beliefs you hold dear (the very beliefs leading you to say such hurtful things to me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until you are ready to respect me as an independent human being with critical thinking skills and the ability to make autonomous decisions, we will never have a relationship. Until you stop viewing me as a project, a lost object to retrieve from the depths of sin, we will never have a relationship. Until you are ready to apologize for the harmful things you have said and done in the name of love, we will never have a relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not coming back to the queerphobia, patriarchy, and racism of evangelicalism. There will be no reunion where I tearfully admit my sins. I will not grovel at your feet, begging for your forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I am not your prodigal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="family" /><category term="lgbtq+" /><category term="christianity" /><summary type="html">“The story of the prodigal son comes to my mind. It is the only way I will be able to deal with this. I’ll wait for you with open arms when you come back home… until then, I’ll pray for you to have your eyes opened by the only true God that you have put on the back burner…“These words, sent to me by my father, may seem innocuous. Maybe they even seem loving or kind. But make no mistake — these words, and the others that accompanied them, are manipulative, abusive, and deeply hurtful.What prompted this message? I came out as bisexual.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/not-your-prodigal.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m not saying I’m Captain Marvel, but…</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/not-saying-captain-marvel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I'm not saying I'm Captain Marvel, but..." /><published>2019-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/not-saying-captain-marvel</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/not-saying-captain-marvel/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;*** CAPTAIN MARVEL SPOILERS ***&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I’m not much of a superhero person; in fact, I’m not much of a &lt;em&gt;movie person&lt;/em&gt; in general. This week, however, I watched Captain Marvel and found myself moved to tears.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Carol’s journey resonates deeply in my body because our paths have been all too similar.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/not-saying-captain-marvel/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/captain-marvel.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Image Credit Marvel Studios&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;She woke up with no memories and found herself being forced to assimilate to a strange culture. I was born into evangelicalism and indoctrinated from birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was told that her power came from an invisible supreme intelligence and could be taken away as easily as it was given; her entire purpose was to serve at the will of this being. I was told that any good deeds or accomplishments I achieve in life are all due to an invisible deity; my entire life purpose was to serve at the will of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carol was taught that she had to suppress her emotions and learn to control them in order to correctly wield the power she had been given — otherwise, she risked destroying herself and others. I was taught that I must suppress my emotions and distrust my body in order to correctly fulfill my purpose in life — otherwise, I risked my own soul and the souls of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were both taught lies in order to further a political agenda and oppress others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve been fighting with one arm tied behind my back, but what happens when I’m finally set free?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carol realizes that the source of her power isn’t the supreme intelligence — it’s &lt;em&gt;her&lt;/em&gt;. She won’t lose her power by rebelling against the system; in fact, she only becomes more powerful. Those who taught her to suppress her emotions were attempting to control what they feared, but rediscovering her authentic self allowed Carol to truly embody the power that was always there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also come to realize that &lt;em&gt;I am powerful&lt;/em&gt;. My emotions are not meant to be suppressed, and they are not wicked. I can and should trust myself. My power doesn’t come from the charitable leftovers of an invisible deity; it comes from within. The more time I spend listening to my body and validating my desires, the more authentic and free I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have nothing to prove to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carol decisively told her abuser that she has nothing to prove to him. He tried — and failed — to bait her into fighting on his terms by relying on the fact that he had conditioned her to crave his approval. I have had to come to terms with the fact that nothing I do will ever be enough to prove myself to certain people from my past. In order to even engage with their arguments, I have to re-enter a space that I have long since left behind. I will never prove anything by lowering myself to their standards, so I’ve had to learn to accept that I have nothing to prove to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Higher, further, faster, baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a moment when Carol discovers she can fly where, between rounds of fighting off enemies, she laughs and lets out an exhilarated scream. Despite the danger, despite the terror literally staring her in the face, Carol feels immense joy in discovering new facets of her authentic self. She takes pleasure in realizing that her power extends far beyond her wildest dreams in spite of the danger she must face. I felt limitless just watching her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I unfortunately can’t fly, I was reminded that my power is greater than I’ve ever been told. Despite the new challenges and dangers that embracing my authentic self will bring into my life, it is exhilarating to become the person I’m meant to be. I am capable of facing my fears and defeating the systems and ideologies that attempt to control me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="christianity" /><category term="feminism" /><summary type="html">*** CAPTAIN MARVEL SPOILERS ***I’m not much of a superhero person; in fact, I’m not much of a movie person in general. This week, however, I watched Captain Marvel and found myself moved to tears.Carol’s journey resonates deeply in my body because our paths have been all too similar. Image Credit Marvel Studios</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/captain-marvel.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ways I Honor My Bisexuality (without kissing women)</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/ways-i-honor-my-bisexuality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ways I Honor My Bisexuality (without kissing women)" /><published>2019-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/ways-i-honor-my-bisexuality</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/ways-i-honor-my-bisexuality/">&lt;p&gt;Bi+ erasure and invisibility often make me feel like my bisexuality doesn’t actually exist unless I’m walking around holding hands with my obviously cis male partner and kissing an obviously cis woman at the same time while wearing a shirt that says “I’M BISEXUAL!” in all caps. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/ways-i-honor-my-bisexuality/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/honor-my-bisexuality.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feeling becomes especially heavy when I am publicly visible with my cishet male partner — my bisexuality sort of fades into the background until it is nonexistent. Thanks to cisheteronormativity, people tend to assume that I am straight because of the relationship I am in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, it is extremely important to me that I find ways to honor and express my bisexuality in daily life. While the idea of publicly kissing a woman while holding my partner’s hand does sometimes sound appealing, there are plenty of other ways I integrate my bisexuality into my life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intaking bi+ media and media created by bi+ folks (even if it isn’t explicitly queer in nature)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a broad category because there are so many forms of queer media! I spend a lot of time reading articles, listening to podcasts, and following topics on social media &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; bisexuality and other queer topics — learning more about our history and staying current on issues we are facing is important to me. However, I also try to prioritize the intake of media that is &lt;em&gt;created by&lt;/em&gt; bi+ folks no matter what the subject matter is. Supporting bi+ creators increases visibility for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listening to music with non-explicitly-male love interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This includes songs with gender neutral pronouns as well as songs about women, and I award bonus points if the artist is also not a cis man. Music receives it’s own category because it is a pervasive aspect of my life — almost every store, restaurant, or car ride features background music. Intentionally curating the music I hear is a small way that I can positively impact my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expressing to my partner when I find other people attractive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was forced to repress my attractions to everyone except cis men for so long that it is an act of resistance and bravery to express aloud when I find someone attractive. My partner is extremely encouraging in this endeavor and we find ourselves bonding over the occasional shared attraction. In this way, an expression of my bisexuality is actually facilitating intimacy-building between me and partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wearing or displaying bi pride colors and symbols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My partner gave me a lovely necklace that displays the bi flag colors, and another dear friend gave me a crescent moon necklace. While the bi colors are fairly self-explanatory, the moon is my personal symbol of bisexuality (see the screenshot below). I also display a bi pride flag in my bedroom, have many pride pins on my backpack, wear a bi pride colored ring stack, and own a multitude of pride-related pieces of clothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/motherfucking-moon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot of a tweet that says &amp;quot;We acknowledge that the whole moon exists even when, from Earth, we can only see part of it. So it really shouldn't be that hard to respect the wholeness of bisexual/pansexual/sexually fluid people even when they're in a monogamous relationship. It's fine to have phases, and outside appearances don't define you. We're the motherfucking moon.&amp;quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This tweet is from a friend who would rather not be named.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mentioning my bisexuality in social media bios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is important to me because it gives people a filter through which they will see all of my posts. By mentioning that I’m bisexual in a place that is fairly visible, I can help ensure that people don’t see pictures of me and my partner and assume I’m straight. When I put it in front of them, they will read what I post on social media through a different lens (which is great, because I interact with the world differently because I’m bi).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recognizing when I have a “celebrity crush” on a non-cis-male individual&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone has a celebrity crush, even those in monogamous relationships. It’s culturally acceptable to have crushes on celebrities, so acknowledging when I have one — no matter their gender — is really important to me in normalizing bisexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joining online communities for LGBTQ+ or bi+ folks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I wish I could surround myself with LGBTQ+ folks in real life who share my experiences, that isn’t always possible, so I intentionally seek out online communities of people who can relate to my daily reality. I’m part of several Facebook groups for varying demographics of LGBTQ+ folks and very active on Twitter. Some of my deepest friendships were formed in those spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating intentional space to honor my bisexuality not only positively impacts my well-being, it fosters intimacy with my partner and allows me to connect with others in deeper, more authentic ways. Even though our identities are not always immediately obvious to outside observers, we are healthier and more embodied when we lean into them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="lgbtq+" /><summary type="html">Bi+ erasure and invisibility often make me feel like my bisexuality doesn’t actually exist unless I’m walking around holding hands with my obviously cis male partner and kissing an obviously cis woman at the same time while wearing a shirt that says “I’M BISEXUAL!” in all caps.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/honor-my-bisexuality.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Queering Eve</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/queering-eve/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Queering Eve" /><published>2019-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/queering-eve</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/queering-eve/">&lt;p&gt;In every sermon and Sunday School lesson about Genesis 3, Eve was always the antagonist of the story. She was the one who disobeyed God, who communicated with the serpent, and who convinced Adam to eat the forbidden fruit. She’s the reason shame befell the human race and the reason God kicked them both out of the garden. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; But what if Eve wasn’t the bad guy, so to speak? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; What happens if we come back to this text with fresh eyes and a different hermeneutic? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/queering-eve/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/queering-eve.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s exactly what &lt;a href=&quot;http://samanthapfield.com/about-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Samantha Field&lt;/a&gt; asked us to do in her breakout session during the Q Christian Fellowship conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;queering-hermeneutics&quot;&gt;Queering Hermeneutics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samantha presented the idea of queering hermeneutics with three main principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Both/And — there are rarely binaries, even when the text seems to present two contradicting concepts. For example, God is &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; alpha &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; omega. Where can we interrupt the idea of binaries in the text?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Instability and disruption — how can we view the text through a lens of disrupting systems of oppression? How can this text be used to subvert, for example, cisheteronormativity or the kyriarchy?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Playing the trickster — sometimes the initial, “obvious” interpretation of the text should be turned upside down. What happens if we call good, evil and evil, good? What can be seen in the text when we flip the script?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She gave a few examples, but quickly turned us loose in groups to practice using these principles on a given passage. My group&lt;a href=&quot;#groupfootnote&quot;&gt;**&lt;/a&gt; ended up with Genesis 3, although our interpretation encompasses most of Genesis 2 as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost everything I’m about to write contradicts what I was taught growing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;returning-to-the-text--our-interpretation&quot;&gt;Returning to the Text — Our Interpretation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the creation of the world, God also created hierarchy. This is inherent to any system in which an all-powerful Being creates autonomous life — those created are automatically subservient to their creator because they do not possess equal knowledge or skills. Thus, Adam and Eve were thrust into a system of power imbalance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God also created the Tree of Life and the Tree of the Knowledge of Good and Evil. The existence of the Tree of Life tells us one of two things: either Adam and Eve were &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; created immortal and needed to eat the fruit of the tree to become immortal, or they &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; created immortal but had to continually eat the fruit in order to stay that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam and Eve were given one rule — do not eat from the Tree of the Knowledge of Good and Evil. Well, Adam was given the rule before Eve was actually created, and it is assumed that he passed it on to Eve. (Unless being created from Adam’s rib automatically gave Eve all the knowledge he possessed as well, but that’s a bit of a stretch.) The consequence of breaking this rule was dire. To quote the NRSV, “for in the day that you eat of it you shall die.” God told them that eating the fruit of this tree would kill them “in the day” that they ate it. God was not threatening the decay and eventual death of their bodies, but a sudden and immediate death as soon as they broke the rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t know for sure what kind of knowledge Adam and Eve had before eating the fruit, but it was obviously limited. Otherwise, the fruit from the Tree of the Knowledge of Good and Evil would have been irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This put the humans in quite a predicament. God was asking them to choose between a life of mediocre, limited knowledge or death. To choose between life under a hierarchy of power differential or death. Their ability to learn and grow was being restricted under penalty of death by a creator who had never, up to this point in the narrative, claimed to love them. God called them “very good,” but this only indicates that God was pleased with the handiwork of what had been created, not that God felt any particular way towards them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the serpent. For unknown reasons, he questioned Eve about what God had told her regarding the fruit. Eve’s answer was a bit of an exaggeration, but since she wasn’t alive when God made the original statement, it’s possible that she was simply repeating what Adam had told her. There’s no evidence to suggest that she willfully lied about the commandment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The serpent, however, challenges God’s statement that eating the fruit would kill the humans. He claims that God doesn’t want them to eat of it because it would cause their eyes to be opened to the knowledge of good and evil — the same knowledge that God possesses. “You will be like God,” he hisses. “You will not die.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eve becomes the heroine of the story when she resolves to call God’s bluff. She decides that obtaining the knowledge of good and evil is worth the risk of death; that she doesn’t want to live under God’s thumb, unable to fully understand the world in which she resides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eve rebelled against the hierarchy God had created and led Adam to do the same. As they ate the fruit, Genesis affirms that the serpent had told them the truth — “the eyes of both were opened,” just as he said would happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When their eyes were opened, Adam and Eve more fully understood their own nakedness, so they covered themselves. They hid from God because their nakedness caused them to be afraid. This makes sense, of course. They had just violated the only command God had given them, but with their newfound knowledge, they understood that the vulnerability represented by their nakedness was no longer something they wished to share with the God who had attempted to restrict their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their clothing was not about shame. Adam and Eve were not ashamed of their nakedness, but fearful of a God who could easily overpower them. They finally fully understood the world, on a level that was “like God,” and they knew that their most private and intimate parts were not safe in God’s presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eve is forced to bear the brunt of the blame. God is angered that the humans have attained the same level of knowledge and curses their existence. As punishment for leading the rebellion against the hierarchy, God extends it even further, placing Eve under the rule of Adam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God also banished them from the garden. The knowledge Adam and Eve obtained from the Tree of the Knowledge of Good and Evil combined with the immortality from the Tree of Life would have practically turned them into gods. This was a clear threat to God’s power, so the humans were sent away to suffer the consequences of their curses and eventually die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Eve did manage to prove that God was a liar. No one died the day they ate the fruit, which is what God originally threatened. Eve also successfully challenged the power structure under which she was forced to live, despite being brutally punished for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eve is &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; victor &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; victim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She shows us that power structures are worth disrupting even if God is the one instituting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She turns on its head the idea that a woman lured man into sin and instead challenges us with the idea that a woman led man into all knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we queer our hermeneutic, Genesis 2-3 becomes a story about a powerful woman who decided that death was better than a life in subservience to an oppressive force. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;groupfootnote&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#42;&amp;#42; Big thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bisexumel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jazzawazz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jazzy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/maguyton&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Morgan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/noblespencer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Spencer&lt;/a&gt; for being part of the group discussion on this passage!&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="christianity" /><category term="lgbtq+" /><category term="feminism" /><summary type="html">In every sermon and Sunday School lesson about Genesis 3, Eve was always the antagonist of the story. She was the one who disobeyed God, who communicated with the serpent, and who convinced Adam to eat the forbidden fruit. She’s the reason shame befell the human race and the reason God kicked them both out of the garden. But what if Eve wasn’t the bad guy, so to speak? What happens if we come back to this text with fresh eyes and a different hermeneutic?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/queering-eve.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Kind of Sex I Thought I Wanted</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-kind-of-sex-i-thought-i-wanted/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Kind of Sex I Thought I Wanted" /><published>2019-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-kind-of-sex-i-thought-i-wanted</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-kind-of-sex-i-thought-i-wanted/">&lt;p&gt;Purity culture trauma left me with a pretty severe case of vaginismus — I could barely insert small tampons, I couldn’t handle a gynecological exam, and I definitely couldn’t have penetrative sex. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/the-kind-of-sex-i-thought-i-wanted/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/the-kind-of-sex-i-thought-i-wanted.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(For more of my purity culture experience, read &lt;a href=&quot;/purity-culture-is-a-complex-trauma&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first discovered that my trouble with tampons was symptomatic of a larger issue, my biggest goal was to &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; have penis-in-vagina sex with my partner. Sure, I wanted to be able to make it through a gyno exam, but that was the least of my worries. When I got married and was unable to have intercourse because of the intense pain, I felt like a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purity culture taught me that it was my wifely duty to have sex with my partner. It also taught me that the only kind of “real sex” was penis-in-vagina intercourse. Having that kind of sex would cause me to lose my virginity (and also lead to destruction if not saved explicitly for heterosexual marriage).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I couldn’t make it happen after both my partner and I saved our virginity for marriage, the shame and sense of failure were overwhelming. I thought that my partner would be dissatisfied and leave me because I wasn’t giving him sex. I thought that I was being a terrible wife because I couldn’t please my partner. I thought that my body was broken and betraying me because it couldn’t do the one sex act it was made to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also in the midst of dealing with extreme emotional trauma surrounding sex. My sex drive was virtually nonexistent, I had extreme anxiety during sexual encounters, and the shame spirals I experienced were crippling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this culminated in months of avoidance. I didn’t want to think about sex, didn’t want to talk about sex, and definitely didn’t want to &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; sex. I felt stuck in a cycle of avoiding all things sexual for months, feeling guilty about not performing my wifely duty for my husband, agreeing to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; sexual, and wishing I was doing anything else — on repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little over a year into our marriage, I finally started going to therapy. I began slowly peeling back the layers of trauma and pain. (It was during this process that I admitted out loud for the first time that “I might be into girls.”) Wounds began to heal, and I started experiencing a desire for sex again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despite all of the mental and emotional healing, my physical problem of vaginismus persisted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overcoming vaginismus became a priority. I was fixated on being able to have intercourse with my partner. So, just before our 2 year anniversary, I started going to a pelvic floor physical therapist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five months of therapy later, the big day arrived. We had PIV sex! My hard work had paid off. I was a ball of emotions — elated, anxious that it had been a fluke, feeling more connected to my partner than ever before, proud of myself, and crying tears of joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even in the midst of feeling so much excitement, the actual experience of intercourse was underwhelming. I was uncomfortable despite the lack of pain and abundance of lube in use. I didn’t &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; much of anything while it was happening, much less anything close to pleasure. I found myself looking forward to when it would be over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried again, of course. And again, and again. Each time I found myself crossing my fingers and hoping that — &lt;em&gt;this time&lt;/em&gt; — it would be different. I so desperately wanted to enjoy it. I had worked so hard to be able to do this! PIV sex was supposed to be great! My partner had been patient for so long while I worked up to this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But each sexual experience with intercourse was disappointing. I felt the shame and fear begin to creep back in. &lt;em&gt;Why can’t you just enjoy this like a normal woman? Why isn’t this pleasurable for your body? Maybe your vagina is still broken. What if you tell your partner that you haven’t been enjoying these sexual experiences? Will he be upset? What if he still ends up leaving you because you could be having intercourse but don’t want to?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found myself consenting once again to sex that I knew, deep down, I didn’t really want to be having. All of the progress I had made with my sexual and bodily autonomy, as well as the trust between my partner and I, was fading. I was moving in the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that cisheteronormative conditioning is a bitch to unlearn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all of the work I had done to rebuild a healthier view of my sexuality — learning that virginity is a construct with no meaning or use other than allowing men to control my sexuality, accepting and cultivating my queerness, beginning to explore my kinks, becoming comfortable with my naked body — I still believed that PIV sex was the best, if not the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt;, type of sex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having this realization was like getting punched in the gut. I spent several weeks unable to think about anything else related to sex. I felt like I had failed, once again, at something sexual — despite the amount of work I had done in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamieleefinch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jamie Lee Finch&lt;/a&gt; created safe space for me to process this during our phone calls, and I was finally able to admit my feelings out loud. She reminded me that it’s okay to not enjoy penetrative sex and that I don’t have an obligation to perform certain sexual acts with my partner (both things I already knew, but shame spirals are emotional quicksand). She also talked me off the ledge of feeling like a failure by pointing out that deep inner perspective changes take time — my body’s emotions won’t always be in sync with what I mentally know to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After shedding a few tears, I realized that I needed to give myself permission to explore what kind of sex I &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; want to be having. I had already spent months arguing with people that the definition of “sex” can include all sorts of things — mutual masturbation, oral, anal, kink, etc. But those things were all theoretical, because &lt;em&gt;to me&lt;/em&gt;, sex was still associated with PIV. A conversation with my body needed to happen (and it is still happening!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m past the initial emotional chaos, I don’t blame myself for holding on to the idea of a sexual hierarchy. After all, it’s the only thing I had ever been taught growing up. My worth as a woman and a wife was almost entirely dependent on the lack of penile presence in my vagina. No wonder I placed PIV sex on a pedestal — it was the only sexual act that could completely alter my inherent value; thus, it must be at the top of the sexual pyramid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few months I’ve been communicating with my body &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; my partner. They have both been patient and endlessly kind as I figure out how to move forward in a way that more accurately acknowledges my sexual preferences. I still feel as though I haven’t made much progress in determining what I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; enjoy, but I have been making great strides in accepting my desires without judgment. The shame spiral is no longer lurking, just waiting for me to realize that I’m failing. I have accepted that PIV sex might never be something I enjoy, and the relief that washed over me with that acceptance was freeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prioritizing my sexual pleasure has finally become more important than the specific sexual acts which provide that pleasure. For now, that means I mostly have sex with myself using an external vibrator while realizing that masturbation is not a “lower form” of sex. It is empowering, healthy, and exactly what my body has been asking me to do. The sexual hierarchy in my brain is slowly crumbling, and in it’s place I am building a sexual mansion in which every room is stunningly beautiful and worth exploring.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="sex" /><summary type="html">Purity culture trauma left me with a pretty severe case of vaginismus — I could barely insert small tampons, I couldn’t handle a gynecological exam, and I definitely couldn’t have penetrative sex.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/the-kind-of-sex-i-thought-i-wanted.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Only She Can Save Me</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/only-she-can-save-me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Only She Can Save Me" /><published>2018-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/only-she-can-save-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/only-she-can-save-me/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/only-she-can-save-me/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/beach-poem.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of me laying on a beach in the shallow water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; I walk daily in a world where &lt;br /&gt;
this picture&lt;br /&gt;
this swimsuit&lt;br /&gt;
this body&lt;br /&gt;
will cast doubt on the truth of my experiences&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was raised in a world where&lt;br /&gt;
this sensuality&lt;br /&gt;
this confidence &lt;br /&gt;
this body &lt;br /&gt;
were regarded as sinful and impure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was taught to believe that&lt;br /&gt;
this sexuality&lt;br /&gt;
this passion&lt;br /&gt;
this body&lt;br /&gt;
would cause men to do terrible things to me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so I spent 23 years repressing&lt;br /&gt;
this beauty &lt;br /&gt;
this freedom&lt;br /&gt;
this body&lt;br /&gt;
to save the souls of men&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but what I’ve come to realize is &lt;br /&gt;
this body&lt;br /&gt;
my body&lt;br /&gt;
SHE&lt;br /&gt;
cannot save anyone but ME&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if only I make space for her to do so&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="feminism" /><category term="sex" /><summary type="html">I walk daily in a world where this picture this swimsuit this body will cast doubt on the truth of my experiences</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/beach-poem.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Purity Culture is a Complex Trauma</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/purity-culture-is-a-complex-trauma/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Purity Culture is a Complex Trauma" /><published>2018-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/purity-culture-is-a-complex-trauma</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/purity-culture-is-a-complex-trauma/">&lt;p&gt;This blog post is a copy of a Facebook post I made, which was based on a Twitter thread. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Find the unrolled Twitter thread &lt;a href=&quot;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1035160280978808833.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, the original Twitter thread &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Carissa12Nicole/status/1035160280978808833&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;amp; the Facebook post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/carissa.nicole/posts/10218018893692610?__xts__[0]=68.ARCfhuMPjUcpqz7pJeWM16JrnfXGYxUYkW5-7CtEbSjEXXTTd5uHiH2xVX7wXmfz7-z2Yb5V5Xg6Ero-6Fln94GbgfsUwYcaZsw04NAZG4yqGyuczneCMZi6gorWM_j45EmTixr4uEI4rHJOlCbYNoYkS8n8J8y1cB9vrFQRACP0fqzy35cz&amp;amp;__tn__=C-R&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/purity-culture-is-a-complex-trauma/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/purity-culture.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cw: sex, purity culture trauma&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(lightly edited for Facebook aka I took out the big bad swears &amp;amp; the tweet numbers)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a few nights ago, I tweeted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“you ever just sit in your bathroom sobbing late at night because purity culture messed up your life &amp;amp; everything feels worse when you’re tired?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone replied &amp;amp; asked how purity culture did that, so here is a definitely-not-comprehensive-barely-begins-to-cover-it thread of my experience with the trauma that is purity culture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: how did #purityculture mess up my life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: how long you got? a thread..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Exvangelical #ChurchToo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;purity culture is the pervasive set of beliefs, structures, &amp;amp; actions that place a heavy focus on the virginity &amp;amp; “physical/spiritual/emotional purity” of women/girls&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it is heavily influenced by patriarchal beliefs such as male headship, women being unable to serve in the same capacity as men in the church (&amp;amp; sometimes world at large), complementarian gender roles (women are made to run the home, men to provide by working), etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it is also heavily influenced by a cisheteronormative/anti-LGBTQ belief system wherein virginity is defined by the lack of PIV sex (the only kind of “real sex”), oral/anal/etc are often considered sinful even WITHIN a hetero marriage, &amp;amp; gender binaries determine sex drive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;church/youth group/Christian school lessons on sex:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;men/boys have out of control sex drives &amp;amp; lust that they can’t control&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;women/girls want love &amp;amp; give sex to get it&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;virginity is a gift for your future husband &amp;amp; losing it cannot be undone&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;losing your virginity is the equivalent to being chewed gum, backwash in a cup, a rose with no petals, tape that has lost it’s stickiness, etc. these illustrations are uniquely applied to women/girls bc it is their responsibility to save this gift for future husband&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;modesty is imperative bc boys/men cannot control their eyes or lust, so it is the job of girls/women to keep them from stumbling. our bodies are dangerous &amp;amp; capable of causing men to sin, thus WE are sinning if we don’t cover up for the sake of men&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;even THOUGHTS are sinful, so you must work overtime to prevent even the slightest hint of sexual thought from entering your brain&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;sex outside het marriage is dirty, an abomination&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;masturbating is a form of cheating on future spouse &amp;amp; also lust, so dirty/sinful also&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;there is a heavy emphasis on how terrible you will feel if you violate any of the purity standards that have been set for you, &amp;amp; so normal &amp;amp; age-appropriate sexual exploration becomes a vicious cycle of shame &amp;amp; guilt (sometimes for something as benign as holding hands!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;purity culture also intentionally withholds sex education, because children who aren’t taught about sex will obviously not think about sex, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this leads to people like me who cannot identify basic body parts well into my college years&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when you spend the first 20-some years of your life trying desperately to repress any sex drive or attraction you might feel bc allowing yourself to feel it would be sinful, &amp;amp; spinning in shame &amp;amp; guilt for failing, it is TRAUMATIC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;purity culture is a complex trauma&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it is a trauma of incidents compiled over a lifetime, no one particular thing ever seeming bad enough to rise to the level of traumatic, but put together it causes many of the same symptoms as sexual assault/abuse/trauma bc it is a form of sexual trauma&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got married &amp;amp; discovered sexuality is not a switch I can flip on as I was taught. Even the thought of having sex WITH MY HUSBAND caused anxiety &amp;amp; panic attacks, &amp;amp; actually attempting sex sent me spiraling in shame &amp;amp; guilt despite knowing “it’s okay now bc I’m married”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have vaginismus as a result of my trauma. This is a pelvic floor condition in which my vaginal muscles involuntarily contract &amp;amp; do not allow anything to enter as well as causing severe pain upon trying. this is also common in sexual abuse/assault survivors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cried myself to sleep for months. not only could I not figure out how to want or enjoy the sex I waited so long to have, but my body was physically betraying me. I was a failure &amp;amp; couldn’t give my husband what he needed. I was taught this was my wifely duty &amp;amp; I was failing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the sense of failure only worsened my shame spiral &amp;amp; we eventually gave up trying. I then felt guilty for being relieved that I didn’t have to think about sex any more, bc thinking about it still made me feel dirty as I had been told to feel my whole life to this point&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually started therapy &amp;amp; have started the long process of sorting through my trauma surrounding sex, but it’s an ongoing process. I’m now also in PT to deal with the physical aspect of vaginismus, but it’s a slow, painful process w/ no guarantee of full recovery&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on top of this, I’m bisexual. I repressed this aspect of myself even deeper than my sexual thoughts about men. I grew up being taught that I would go to hell, that LGBTQ+ folks are abominations, sexual perverts, disgusting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;despite changing theology &amp;amp; being LGBTQ+ affirming by this point, I still couldn’t admit to myself or anyone that I was bi. it took months of intense inner work in therapy to even come out to myself. imagine growing up &amp;amp; being instilled with such disgust for WHO YOU ARE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was never given space or tools to develop a healthy sexuality. I’m basically in 2nd puberty, trying to relearn &amp;amp; reconstruct my sexuality from the ground up after doing so much work to dismantle the lies I was given as a framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have trouble touching my own or my husband’s genitals, bc they were portrayed as dirty, gross, &amp;amp; sinful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggled for months with the idea that I couldn’t have real sex without being able to have PIV, but sex is so much more than that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my sex drive, when it does make an appearance, is still often guilt &amp;amp; shame ridden. it is so deeply ingrained in my body that sexual thoughts are evil, even when they are about my husband, that shame &amp;amp; guilt often override any sexual desire I might have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if I’m not careful, I still fall into shame cycles about the fact that I’m “still a technical virgin” because a penis has never graced my vagina with it’s presence. when you’re told for so long that’s what defines sex, it’s hard to break out of that mindset&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I harmed myself &amp;amp; my husband by saying yes so many times at the beginning of our marriage when I really didn’t want to. I thought I was sinning if I refused him sex, &amp;amp; so I forced myself to try. he struggles to trust my yes now, &amp;amp; I struggle to not resent his asking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪when I am able to muster up a bit of sex drive &amp;amp; we’re able to get past all the other baggage surrounding sex, I am unable to communicate DURING sex. I often feel disembodied, unable to speak or make any noise at all, unable to tell him what I like or dislike bc I DON’T KNOW‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪how am I supposed to know how I like to be pleasured when I was never supposed to touch myself? when I still feel dirty touching myself? when, even though it’s now “okay,” my body feels like a minefield &amp;amp; touching or thinking the wrong thing will give me a panic attack?‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪to circle back a little, I was also pressured to marry young simply by virtue of the culture I was in. “it is better to marry than to burn with passion,” &amp;amp; I was expected to become a wife &amp;amp; mother anyway. I am forever grateful that Jared has grown alongside me &amp;amp; we fit well‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪I was told that romance &amp;amp; “true love” would turn into sexual desire, that I didn’t need to worry about sexual compatibility or attraction bc it would fall into place if I followed the rules &amp;amp; stayed pure. turns out, I’m not all that sexually attracted to my husband&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪I’m gonna end this for now, but I really could probably write an entire book about how purity culture harmed me &amp;amp; messed up my life (bc I don’t wanna hear how my sexuality isn’t a big deal &amp;amp; my marriage should be able to function well despite all this)‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪this experience isn’t uncommon. there are SO MANY people who have been harmed by purity culture, &amp;amp; if you want to tell your story too, feel free to quote tweet or reply! I’ll end by linking some resources if you want to better understand the trauma that is purity culture‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪- everything &lt;a href=&quot;http://samanthapfield.com/tag/purity-culture/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Samantha Field writes about purity culture&lt;/a&gt; is fantastic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪- highly recommend Northwest Institute On Intimacy &amp;amp; Dr. Tina Schermer Sellers book &amp;amp; blog, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinaschermersellers.com/2015/03/24/how-the-purity-movement-causes-symptoms-of-sexual-abuse/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here’s a good starting point‬&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪- over at Love, Joy, Feminism there are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.patheos.com/blogs/lovejoyfeminism/the-purity-culture/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SO MANY posts&lt;/a&gt; to help you understand purity culture &amp;amp; the harm it does&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪- there’s an &lt;a href=&quot;https://ikdgstories.tumblr.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;entire Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to publishing stories from those who came out of the purity culture associated with “I Kissed Dating Goodbye”‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‪- speaking of IKDG, even the author has acknowledged the harm his ideas did &amp;amp; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://joshharris.com/documentary/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;creating a documentary&lt;/a&gt; about it‬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so there’s the sparknotes version of how purity culture has messed up my life &amp;amp; some resources, but feel free to ask any clarifying questions&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="christianity" /><category term="lgbtq+" /><category term="feminism" /><category term="sex" /><summary type="html">This blog post is a copy of a Facebook post I made, which was based on a Twitter thread. Find the unrolled Twitter thread here, the original Twitter thread here, &amp;amp; the Facebook post here.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/purity-culture.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bekah Learns Boundaries</title><link href="https://carissanicolewinn.com/bekah-learns-boundaries/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bekah Learns Boundaries" /><published>2018-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://carissanicolewinn.com/bekah-learns-boundaries</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://carissanicolewinn.com/bekah-learns-boundaries/">&lt;p&gt;The concept of setting boundaries is still relatively new to me. I didn’t know until recently that it is acceptable &amp;amp; normal to put boundaries on relationships. I thought that expending emotional energy on every person who entered my life was just the way it had to be. So this past week, I exercised my new understanding of this topic to lay down some pretty intense boundaries with someone who definitely deserved all the snark that came along with it. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; I recently received a message from someone I knew in college; I’ll call her Bekah. We played sports together, but were never very close. I wasn’t very close to many people, actually, because it’s hard to get close to people at a conservative Baptist college when you are secretly deconstructing your entire belief system. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Anyway, I haven’t spoken to Bekah in almost 3 years, but she just couldn’t help herself. She sent me a message about the fact that I came out as bisexual, &amp;amp; I felt compelled to respond. Jared helped me write the message (&amp;amp; he also made me take out all the &lt;em&gt;big bad swears&lt;/em&gt; *pouty face*). Below is the text of our messages. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/bekah-learns-boundaries/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post-headers/bekah-learns-boundaries.png&quot; alt=&quot;graphic displaying the title of the article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dear Carissa,
I read the status you posted about a week ago. First, I would like to apologize for not writing this sooner. There have been many hours spent in thought over how to go about this message, so I pray that my speech and motivation is understood. Carissa, something that has honestly really been bothering me about what you posted is that you call yourself more of a Christian for being bisexual. Here is my problem with that, no where does it say that in God’s word. In fact, it says the opposite of that, which is why I am writing to you now. I am truly and deeply concerned about you and the path you are on. My concern stems from the fact that God calls what you are doing sin. I was looking through the Bible for verses on this exact topic and came to find it called nothing but sin. Please understand, I can only claim it as sin because that is what God’s word says. In Romans 1:21-32, it says, “For although they knew God, they did not honor him as God or give thanks to him, but they became futile in their thinking, and their foolish hearts were darkened. 22 Claiming to be wise, they became fools, 23 and exchanged the glory of the immortal God for images resembling mortal man and birds and animals and creeping things.
24 Therefore God gave them up in the lusts of their hearts to impurity, to the dishonoring of their bodies among themselves, 25 because they exchanged the truth about God for a lie and worshiped and served the creature rather than the Creator, who is blessed forever! Amen.
26 For this reason God gave them up to dishonorable passions. For their women exchanged natural relations for those that are contrary to nature; 27 and the men likewise gave up natural relations with women and were consumed with passion for one another, men committing shameless acts with men and receiving in themselves the due penalty for their error.
28 And since they did not see fit to acknowledge God, God gave them up to a debased mind to do what ought not to be done. 29 They were filled with all manner of unrighteousness, evil, covetousness, malice. They are full of envy, murder, strife, deceit, maliciousness. They are gossips, 30 slanderers, haters of God, insolent, haughty, boastful, inventors of evil, disobedient to parents, 31 foolish, faithless, heartless, ruthless. 32 Though they know God’s righteous decree that those who practice such things deserve to die, they not only do them but give approval to those who practice them.” This passage clearly shows that God sees homosexuality and bisexuality as a dishonorable passion, something that should not be done, and deserving of death. So you see, if I were to celebrate what you are doing then I would be giving approval to something that I know God says is wrong. By doing so, I would not be acting lovingly toward you, but hating you. It is not an act of love to watch and even encourage someone to continue living in sin, allowing them to get deeper and more attached to it. That is why I apologized at the beginning of this letter. I have allowed a week to go by without confronting you and trying to help you with this temptation. Do not think I have written this letter to make fun of or scorn you. I wrote this because I care about you and am extremely worried that you are headed down a path that leads to judgment. I do not want that for you! A few years ago, you encouraged me in my time of need. I am sorry I have not been there for you in the same way. There are more verses I found on this topic and would be happy to send your way if you would so desire. Carissa, I am praying for you and I hope to speak to you soon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dear Bekah,
I wanted to write back to let you know that your motivation was understood perfectly. Let me explain. We haven’t been friends for a while now. In fact, we haven’t even been social media friends, not even “facebook friends” for what little that even means. You are not &amp;amp; have not been involved in my life for several years. And based on that fact, what would make you think that you have the right, the relationship, or the position to write a message like this to me? Isn’t “building a relationship” supposed to be the first step in speaking into someone’s life? Why in the world would you think that you have any authority or reason to say any of this? You know absolutely nothing about me. And honestly, you don’t really want to. You didn’t care about my life before I came out and you don’t care now, you only feel a personal responsibility to tell me these things because of your own conviction. That’s why your motivation is selfish. You didn’t write this message actually thinking that it would have any effect on me. You wrote it for YOU. You were so bothered by my coming out post that you needed to clear your own conscience and be able to say “I did what I could” as if it was your responsibility, in the process ladening me with the same generic cookie-cutter thought process that I’ve been around my entire life. Don’t insult me by pretending I haven’t heard it all before. I understand that in your mind the logic is so airtight that you think “if Carissa believes otherwise, it must be because she forgot”. But that isn’t how this works. I did not forget, the logic is not airtight, and wasting your time writing out all the talking points you should be well aware I learned at the same school as you is just a product of the very dangerous presumption that your theology is undeniably correct to the letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, a small helpful hint for the next time you feel like writing a “convicting” message to someone you haven’t seen or spoken to in YEARS &amp;amp; who you weren’t even that close to in the first place:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your motives are not subtle and I promise people can and will continue to see right through them. Approaching topics like this from a holier-than-thou, “I possess knowledge that you don’t” standpoint is only going to alienate others, not convince them. If you believe your purpose as a Christian is to evangelize non-believers (which I am not, for the record), this is the opposite of how to achieve it. No reasonable person would actually believe that a message like this would have any impact on me or my life decisions. Why did you think it would mean something to me? You didn’t. It was for you to be able to say you did it. Why do you think I even care what you think or how YOU interpret the Bible? You can’t claim a monopoly on “Biblical truth” and tote it as the clear and obvious interpretation when the Evangelical church can’t even agree within itself on what is “clear”, let alone the whole of Christianity across the world. Don’t talk to me about “what God says” and expect that to have weight when Christians can’t even agree what God says. Ironically I probably know what you believe about this better than you do, because I put in the work studying it &amp;amp; deciding that it was wrong. I would be willing to bet money that you’ve never given serious, genuine study to the topic of LGBTQ+ “issues”. You just believed what you were taught. I have read hundreds of books &amp;amp; articles, watched lectures, done word studies. Meanwhile you cherry pick a handful of verses, the meaning of which someone else told you and you never gave it a second thought. Your certainty comes from a lifetime of conditioning and insulation from outside thought, not the strength of your belief itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope writing this made you feel better, because you wrote it out of a selfish &amp;amp; condescending desire to fix me. I imagine you also wrote it out of disgust, because I know that you once said you would quit cross country if you found out there was a gay person on the team. Well surprise, I was there the whole time. Luckily I didn’t have to tolerate your homophobia as badly as the other LGBTQ+ people surrounding you. Your interpretation of Scripture leads to the suicides &amp;amp; deaths of hundreds of LGBTQ+ people every year. There are many studies showing this. No good tree bears bad fruit. Your theology bears bad fruit. Period. I don’t have any fanciful ideas that I can change your mind on this, because if you’re the kind of abrasively dogmatic person who writes a message like this to someone you barely know, I can only imagine the kind of damage you would do to an LGBTQ+ person who has the misfortune of knowing you in real life. I want it to be very clear that I know you haven’t studied this, &amp;amp; I want it to be very clear that I actually have. I don’t need you to send me more Bible verses on the topic. I know &amp;amp; could quote to you all 7 “clobber passages”, &amp;amp; I could exegete each one &amp;amp; tell you why I don’t believe they say the things you are claiming. Your conservative white American English Bible is not “clear” on much of anything, &amp;amp; I’m tired of people like you trying to weaponize it against me. I don’t want your prayers. I’m not experiencing temptation. &amp;amp; I most certainly don’t want your homophobic “help” with this. Abandon your pretentious “love” &amp;amp; condescending “apologies”; they will only do people harm.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="christianity" /><category term="lgbtq+" /><summary type="html">The concept of setting boundaries is still relatively new to me. I didn’t know until recently that it is acceptable &amp;amp; normal to put boundaries on relationships. I thought that expending emotional energy on every person who entered my life was just the way it had to be. So this past week, I exercised my new understanding of this topic to lay down some pretty intense boundaries with someone who definitely deserved all the snark that came along with it. I recently received a message from someone I knew in college; I’ll call her Bekah. We played sports together, but were never very close. I wasn’t very close to many people, actually, because it’s hard to get close to people at a conservative Baptist college when you are secretly deconstructing your entire belief system. Anyway, I haven’t spoken to Bekah in almost 3 years, but she just couldn’t help herself. She sent me a message about the fact that I came out as bisexual, &amp;amp; I felt compelled to respond. Jared helped me write the message (&amp;amp; he also made me take out all the big bad swears *pouty face*). Below is the text of our messages.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://carissanicolewinn.com/bekah-learns-boundaries.png" /></entry></feed>